[muffled shriek]
- 嗨,我叫蓝尼
- Hi. l'm Lenny. - [muffled speech]
噢,小朋友,我吓着你了吗？ 真对不起
Oh, little buddy, did l scare you? l'm sorry.
醒醒啊,别担心,我马上放你走
Wake up. Okay, don't worry about it, l'll get you out in a jiffy.
小虫儿,别紧张,等一下就好
Keep holding your breath, little wormie.
- 蓝尼 - 马上来,法兰奇
- Yo, Lenny. - l'm coming, Frankie.
- 快呀,快来,老爸在等我们 - 马上好...成啦
- [Frankie] Move it. Pop's waiting. - Here we go. And gotcha.
好了,朋友,你自由了 现在快逃吧
Okay, buddy, you're free. Now escape.
逃吧, 高呼自由万岁
Just go. Cry freedom.
[shrieks]
- 你差点儿把我吓出心脏病！ - 蓝尼,你在干嘛？
- You almost gave me a heart attack. - What are you doing?
啥？我...呃...我刚才...
l was just...
摘花给你
picking you some flowers.
嘿,妈说过,不可以随便打人
Hey, Mom said it's not okay to hit. [yelps]
妈不在这儿
Mom's not here.
[hums Jaws theme]
别！
Don't.
[Lenny] Don't.
- 那歌听得我发毛 - 啥!? 这是咱们的主题曲啊
- That song gives me the creeps. - Whaddya mean? lt's our theme song.
他们都走了吗? 他们都走了吗?
[interference] Are they gone? Are they gone?
你确定?
You sure?
南礁的市民们早安 我是凯蒂・辛文,随时为您报导新闻
Good morning, Southside Reef. I'm Katie Current, keeping it current.
我们刚接获官方证实 鲨鱼帮已经走了
We've received official confirmation the sharks are gone.
重复... 鲨鱼帮已经走了
I repeat: the sharks are gone.
Don't worry
# 别担心 #
# 没啥事 # [片名: 鲨鱼黑帮/鲨鱼故事]
About a thing
# 琐事烦恼都会过去 #
Every little thing
Is gonna be all right
# 别担心 #
Don't worry
# 没啥事 #
About a thing
鲔鱼协会会员
Tuna Turner.
孔雀蛤克罗恩
Mussel Crowe.
虾子杰希卡
Jessica Shrimpson.
鳕鱼斯图尔特
Cod Stewart.
[seal barks]
接着为您报导 一位母亲怎么生了800个宝宝?
[Katie] Up next, a mother of 800 tells us how she does it all.
但首先,现场交给洁妮丝 为您报导交通路况
But first, over to Janice for the traffic report.
谢谢,凯蒂, 礁际95号公路轻微塞车
Thanks, Katie. Slight congestion here on the InterReef 95.
有只鲭鱼翻车 有关当局正试图安抚他
There's an overturned mackerel. Authorities are trying to calm him down.
大家快拿手机打给老板 因为你一定会迟到
Get out those shell phones and call in to the boss, 'cause you'll be late.
#%^#$&%*#!...
[garbled yelling]
别对着我骂xxx脏话 你妈就是我妈!
Don't you yell at me. My mother is your mother, okay.
[ragga scatting]
- 没错,是假的 - 假的?我孵了整整8年!
- Yup. lt's fake. - Fake? l worked eight years on that.
# 琐事烦恼 #
About a thing
Every little thing
# 都会过去 #
Is gonna be all right
[silence]
[groans]
最新的盖洛普民调显示 民众恐惧鲨鱼的程度达到历史新高
According to the latest Scallop Poll, fear of sharks is at an all-time high.
敬请收看晚间更深入的报导
Join us tonight for an in-depth report.
我们还要生活在这种阴影下多久?
How long must this reef live under siege?
我们之中难道就没有英雄?
Is there no hero among us?
有谁能铲除这些鲨鱼黑帮份子?
Who can stop this shark menace?
嗨～我是奥斯卡, 你以为你知道,但是你绝对想不到
Hi, l'm Oscar. You might think you know, but you have no idea.
[rap music]
欢迎来我的小窝 这是另一半人才能享受的美好生活
Welcome to my crib. The good life, the way the other half lives.
瞧瞧, 60寸平面高解析电视
Check it out, l got my 60'' high-def, flat-screen TV
5.1环绕音响 令人沉迷的CD, DVD, PlayStation
with 6-speaker surround, CD, DVD, PlayStation hook-up
甚至还有8轨胶片放影机 如果你很...
and an 8-track player for days when you're feeling a little... [beatbox]
怀旧...的话
old school. [laughs]
即使像我这种影剧界大老
'Cause even a superstar Mack daddy fish like me
还是需要生活的基本配备...
has to have the basic necessities.
对呀! 比方说 "钱", 哈哈哈
Yeah, like money. [laughs]
孩子们,正经点儿,怎么可以打乱我的梦想呀
Come on, Shorties. Why ya'll messin' with my fantasy?
因为你穷得要命,穷到连自己姓什么都忘了
'Cause you so broke, your baloney has no first name.
好笑, 真是好笑
That's very funny.
嘿, 奥斯卡 我在这儿, 我得和你谈谈
Hey, Oscar. Over here. l gotta talk to ya.
- 待在那儿, 来, 帮我拿一下 - 奥斯卡, 你这大腕
- Be right there. Hang onto these. - Oscar, you da fish.
喂, 老兄
Yo, doo.
哟, 老疯乔
Yo, Crazy Joe.
现在你住进了阁楼套房 我能做你的财务顾问吗?
Now that you live in that penthouse, can l be your financial advisor?
那只是广告看板呀, 老疯乔
That's a billboard, Crazy Joe.
你住在看板里? - 不 还说我疯哩!
You live in a billboard? And they call me crazy.
- 奥斯卡, 看看谁来啦!
- Hey, Oscar. Look who came to visit. - [shrieks]
- 吓着你了吧, 哈哈 - 别这样!
- [Shorties] Gotcha. - No. Don't do that.
- 孩子们, 你们现在该在学校吧 - 你也该在单位呀
- Shouldn't you be in school? - Shouldn't you be at work?
马上回我一枪,嗯?你这小灵精
Right back at me, huh? Little smart mouth.
瞧, 我要去上班了 你们可别惹麻烦喔
Look, l'm on my way. Stay outta trouble, all right?
- 还有～把看板清了 - 待会儿见
- And clean that stuff up. - See ya.
[ intro from Car Wash]
待会儿见,奥斯卡
See ya, Oscar. [laughs]
# 怎么说,怎么说 #
Say what, say what
# 洗车,洗车 #
Car wash, car wash
哟,怎么了,伙计? 大"奥"我来了
Yo, what's up, fellas? Big O's in the house.
怎么了?
What's up?
嘿,大家好
Hey. Reef side.
- 嗨,强森, 午餐时间到了吗? - 你才刚来耶
- Yo, Johnson, is it lunch yet? - You just got here.
这才是重点,呵呵
That's my point.
嗨,耳机仔
Hey, Headphone Guy.
- 小姐们,真漂亮 - 嗨, 奥斯卡
- Lookin' good, ladies. - Hey, Oscar.
别跳砸咯
Keep up the bad work.
唔?
Huh?
我已经打过卡了?
l'm already punched in?
安姬
Angie.
早,需要什么服务?
Good morning. Can l help you?
洗一下再上光
[deep] One wash and lube, please.
- 热腊? - 行
- Hot wax? - Please.
海藻刮擦?我们有特价喔!
Kelp scrape? We're having a special.
好啊, 现在是交配季节 我一定会走桃花运
Why not? lt is mating season, and l'm feelin' lucky.
赛斯鲸鱼洗车,极品洗车,价钱...
Sykes' Whale Wash. A whale of a wash, and the price,...
感觉好幸福喔 [奥斯卡爱安姬]
oh, my gosh.
嗯嗯,嗯嗯
Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
顺便建议你来个磨光服务? 可消除起皱和盐性磨损
May l suggest a barnacle peel? Removes lines and salt damage.
- 好 - 嗨,安姬
- Good. - Hey, Ang.
- 喔, 老天,嗨, 奥斯卡 - 谢谢你替我罩着
- Oh, my gosh. Hi, Oscar. - Thanks for covering for me.
喂, 对不起, 安姬得先接另一通电话
Yo, l'm sorry, Dun. Angie needs to get her freak on.
请你等一下好吗, 谢谢
Would you hold for one moment, please? Thanks.
- 奥斯卡 - 来吧, 安姬宝贝, 来和我跳支舞
- Oscar. - Come on, Ang. Dance with me, mama.
我来唱 # 明天我就要发财了 #
Let me see it. Tomorrow I will be rich...
- 快呀 - 少来, 奥斯卡, 你想让我被炒鱿鱼呀!
- Come on. - Oscar. You're gonna get me fired.
你被炒鱿鱼? 绝不可能发生的
Please, you fired? That can't happen.
因为那样的话 我就再也找不到理由来上班了
'Cause then l would have absolutely no reason to come to work.
你是哄我的吧
Oh, you don't mean that.
我说真的, 你是我最好的朋友
Course l do. You're like my best friend.
[gasps]
[groans]
听着, 你认为这个如何...
Listen, tell me what you think about this.
这可是我这辈子最好的主意
This is like the best idea ever, all right.
这是保证致富的极品妙计
lt's a sure thing, guaranteed cash extravaganza.
- 瓶装过滤水 - 喔! 别!
- Bottled water. - Oh, no.
我只要老板预付我下个月薪水
All l need is an advance on my paycheck from the boss
然后,安姬,我马上走人, 我...就...咻!
and, Ang, l am out of this place. l mean, l am... pschoo!
奥斯卡
Oscar.
与其和老板谈你的又一个快速致富法
lnstead of getting in Mr. Sykes' face with another get-rich-quick scheme,
不如做你拿手的活儿... 你的工作
go do something you're actually good at: your job,
起码你现在还有工作
which by some miracle you still have.
噢
Oh.
差点儿忘了
l almost forgot.
-我带了早餐给你 - 不会吧,甜甜圈?
- l brought you some breakfast. - You didn't. Kelpy Kremes?
你的最爱 顺便说一句...线上还有人在等
Your favorite. By the way, you're still on hold.
噢,老天!
Oh, my gosh!
谢谢你等在线上,忙的不得了
Thank you for holding. Busy, busy.
走! 我能为您服务吗?
Go. How can l help you?
[muffled voice]
对不起, 赛斯先生正在开会
No, l'm sorry. Mr. Sykes is at a meeting right now.
晚点儿才会回来
He won't be back till later.
我的小宝贝们今早好吗?
How are my little babies this morning?
想我吗? 都好吗?
You miss me? You doin' good?
嗯? 嗯?
Huh? Huh?
瞧,赛斯
You see, Sykes,
这是鱼吃鱼的世界 你不去吃,就会被吃
it's a fish-eat-fish world. You either take or you get taken.
[winces]
有些事不必明说我也懂 就这样吧? 说完了吧?
Truer words have never been spoken. ls that it? We done?
现在,你和我,咱们俩共事很久很久了
Now, you and me, we worked together a long, long, long time.
拜托,唐・李诺,这和工作不一样
Please, Don Lino, it's hardly been like work.
- 你知道... - 我最欣赏你这一点
- You know... - l love that about you.
让我说完... 我一生都为了我两个儿子
Let me finish. That l've lived my life for my sons.
- 抚养他们,保护他们 - 你是最好的父亲!
- Raising and protecting them... - You're the best!
我说得对吧? 我说得对还是错? 是对的吧?
He's the best, right? Am l right or am l wrong? Am l right?
- 我总是教他们... - 对吧?
- lt's all been to prepare... - Right?
- 总是教他们... - 抱歉
- ...to prepare them... - Sorry.
...让他们将来能够继承我礁镇的事业 这一天终于到了
...for the day they run the reef. Well, today is that day.
- [sighs] - [record scratches]
路卡
Luca.
# 我喜欢大屁股,我不能撒谎 #
I like big butts And I cannot lie
# 你的另一些兄弟… #
You other brothers...
老板...大屁股...呵呵
Hey, boss. Big Butts. [chuckles]
蠢!
Oi vey!
长话短说吧... 今天开始,法兰奇和蓝尼说了算,懂吧
Long story short, from now on you work for Frankie and Lenny.
- 明白吗?
- Capiche? - [Sykes laughs]
蓝尼? 法兰奇还差不多 蓝尼? 你一定是开玩笑吧
Lenny? Frankie, l understand. But Lenny? You can't be serious.
我说真的,经营事业不是光靠骼膊
l'm dead serious. lt takes more than muscle to run things.
蓝尼有头脑,这点可是很特别的
Now Lenny, he's got the brains. That's somethin' special.
- 对呀,他很特别没错 - 你什么意思?
- He's special all right. - What does that mean?
- 没什么,我只是说… - 我叫你过来
- Nothing. l'm just sayin'... - l bring you in here,
当着面跟你说事情 然后,居然你说啥来着?
look you in the eye, tell you what's what, and what?
- 啥? - 什么啥?
- What? - What ''what''?
是你先说啥的
You said ''what'' first.
我没先说,我是问你,你说啥?
l didn't say what, l asked you what.
不. 你说,然后啥,我才问啥
You said ''And then, what?'' l said ''What?''
不,我说什么啥,到底是啥什么?
No, l said ''what what'', like what what?
- 你的确先说啥 - 你在嘲笑我?
- You said ''what'' first. - Now you're making fun of me?
不不不,你误会了
No, you misunderstood.
对不起,爸,我们迟了 蓝尼发生了意外,他"意外"出生了,呵呵
Sorry we're late, Pop. Lenny had an accident. He was born.
哼哼,你真是个搞笑天才
[sarcastic laugh] You're a comic genius.
我的意思是,那孩子成不了杀手
Look, all l'm saying is the kid ain't exactly no killer.
蓝尼是个杀手,你给我听清楚没有? 一个冷血杀手,看看他
My Lenny is a killer. You hear me? A cold-blooded killer. Look at him.
嗯?
Huh?
够了! 够了!你出局了
That's it! That's it! You are out!
啥? 我出局是啥意思?
What? [high-pitched] Whaddya mean l'm ''out?''
- 你被炒鱿鱼了
- You're fired. - [Sykes screams]
另外,你还得开始付钱给我
And on top of that, you're gonna have to start payin' me.
为啥?
For what?
你的小鲸鱼洗车店的保护费
So nothing happens to your little Whale Wash.
欢迎来奥斯卡的小窝
[Oscar] Welcome to Oscar's crib.
满是60寸高粘浆的舌头,口溃疡,蛀牙
60-foot slime-covered tongue with canker sores, swim-in cavities,
还有布满浮游生物的牙齿 让我觉得...
and plankton-encrusted teeth for when l feel a bit... [grunts]
过气
old school.
别抱怨啦,奥斯卡 这还不算太糟糕
Stop your moaning, Oscar. lt could be a lot worse, you know.
没错,这捞什子工作还好 看起来像你就更糟啦
That's true. l could have this job and look like you. [laughs]
谁在我后面? 谁在我后面? 来击个掌
Who's behind me? Whoever's behind me better give me some.
[rumbling]
消化不良,她要吐啦!
lndigestion. She's gonna blow!
等等...耳机仔还在里面
Wait! Headphone Guy is still in there!
[dance music]
我来救你了...耳机仔!
l got you, Headphone Guy!
[belch]
[laughs]
- 你以为还会更糟糕吗? - 对呀...还好我没像你一样
- Still think it could be worse? - Yeah. l could look like you.
真风趣...看你还笑的出来吗!
Y'all funny. Well, see if you laugh at this.
[whale moans]
肥皂弄进眼睛了! 肥皂弄进眼睛了!
Soap in the eye! Soap in the eye!
没事,没事, 我会给你些优惠券
lt's all right. l'll get you some coupons,
再给你免费打热腊...如何?
a free hot wax and all that. You like that?
- 好了,继续吧,大家伙 - 谢谢,奥斯卡
- All right, go ahead, big baby. - Thanks, Oscar.
好了
All right.
- 伯尼,瞧瞧这谁呀? - 正好是咱们要找的鱼
- Well, look who it is, Bernie. - Just the fish we're looking for.
老板现在要见你 就现在
The boss be needin' to see you right now.
- 现在 - 而尼,伯尼
- Right now. - Ernie. Bernie.
我的水母兄弟,你们好呀
My jellyfish brothers. Boo-ya-ka.
嘿,怎么了,伙计? 真高兴见到你们...唔?
Hey, what's up, man? Man, it's good to see y'all... Huh?
你说啥,安姬?好,知道了
What'd you say, Ang? Okay.
各位,我得到那儿去
Fellas, l'm gonna go ahead over there.
# 别担心... #
But don't worry
# 虽然日子不顺利 #
[beatbox] About a thing
# 琐事烦恼都会过去 #
'Cause every little thing Is gonna be all right...
唱啥都没用
That's not the way you sing that song, mon.
[shrieks]
赛斯...我异父异母的兄弟 你好呀,宝贝?
Sykes, my brother from another mother. What the deezy, baby?
告诉我今天好吗?
Show me dat. What's goin' down?
嘿,宝贝,今天是个好日子 来击个掌...击掌
Hey, baby, this is all gravy today. Now snap your fin... Snap it.
- 怎么不击? - 奥斯卡
- You're not snappin' it... - Oscar.
别紧张,很多白鱼像你一样不会击掌
Hey, don't sweat it. A lot of white fish can't do it.
- 你就坐下吧, 好吗? - 谢谢
- Would you just sit down, okay? - Thank you.
我把帐本都看了一下 你欠我五千元
l've been goin' over my markers. You're into me for five grand.
- 五千...懂吧? - 五千? 你搞错了吧,五千!
- 5 G's, okay? - 5 G's? Man, you trippin'? 5 G's.
怎么会? 现在想起来了吧?
Oh, yeah? See if this refreshes your memory.
哇...不得了...瞧瞧
That's crazy, look at that.
你把一切都写下来,才不会忘记
You wrote everything down so you wouldn't forget.
这就是为什么你是老板我是伙计
This a perfect example of why you're in management, and l'm not.
干的好
You go, boy.
我现在得付唐・李诺保护费 你欠我就等于欠他
l have to pay Don Lino protection, so everything you owe me, you owe him.
- 这怎么算的? - 简单...食物链
- How you figure that? - Simple. The food chain.
瞧...最上面是唐・李诺 下面是我,再下来就是一般的鱼
See, on top there's Don Lino. There's me, and there's regular fish.
- 那是我 -不是
- That's me. - No.
这是浮游生物, 这是单细胞生物...
There's plankton, there's amoebas...
- 然...后...就是我? - 马上就到你了
- Then there's me? - l'm gettin' there.
这是珊瑚, 这是岩石,这是鲸鱼粪, 然后就是你
There's coral, there's rocks, there's whale pooh, and then there's you.
这太糟了
That's messed up.
所以如果唐压榨我就等于是压榨你
So if Don Lino's squeezin' me, he's squeezin' you.
- 什么? - 奥斯卡
- What? - Oscar.
对不起
Sorry.
- 别生气,老板,去找乐子吧 - 去找乐子吧
- Easy, boss, find your happy place. - Happy place.
有他在,哪儿有乐子可找! 我可是说正经的
There is no happy place with him here. [high-pitched] l'm serious.
好好好...求求你... 再多给我点时间
Okay, please. Please, just gimme some time.
就这点小要求 我求求你,塞斯,求求你
That's all l'm asking. l'm begging you, Sykes. Please. Please.
好吧
All right.
因为我欣赏你 我给你24小时来付清
'Cause l like you, l'm gonna give you 24 hours to pay up.
所有这些? 我怎么付法呀?
All of it? How am l supposed to do that?
那是你的问题 明天把五千拿去赛马场给我,否则...
That's your problem. Bring my 5,000 clams to the track tomorrow, or else.
- 否则如何? - 我手下会解释给你听
- Or else what? - The boys'll explain.
[both laugh]
不好受
- [sizzling] - [Oscar] Unpleasant.
五千元?
[Angie] 5,000 clams?
你欠赛斯先生五千元?
You borrowed 5,000 clams from Mr. Sykes?
奥斯卡,你怎么会搞成这样?
Oscar, why do you get yourself into these situations?
我也不知道,安姬
l don't know, Ang.
只是日子不好过呀 我只是个大池塘里的一条小鱼
lt's just hard, all right, because l'm a little fish in a big pond.
很大很大的池塘 海洋
A really big pond. The ocean.
我只是个无名小卒 我要那些
l'm a nobody. l want some of that.
- 桑切斯太太? - 啥?
- Mrs. Sanchez? - What?
# 女人的夜晚 # # 噢,多美妙的夜晚… #
It's ladies' night, Oh, what a night...
呃...不是啦 那个
Ew. No. That.
礁顶 大人物住的地方
The top of the reef. Where the somebodies live.
我想发财,成名,像他们一样 但是...我却困在下面
l wanna be rich and famous like them, but l'm stuck down here.
下面这儿怎么啦?
Well, what's wrong with down here?
我告诉你下面有什么不对
l'll tell you what's wrong with down here.
还记得我爸吗? 他一辈子都在洗车店打工
Remember my dad? He worked at the Wash his whole life.
# 哦…孩子... #
Ooh, child...
他是刷舌的头号人物
[Oscar] He was the number one tongue scrubber.
每年都是...连续25年
Every year for 25 years.
对我来说,再洗车是海里最酷的工作
To me, working at the Wash was the coolest job in the ocean.
然后发生了一件 我一辈子都不会忘记的事
But then I learned something I will never forget.
奥斯卡的爸爸是刷舌工,哈哈哈!
Oscar's dad's a tongue scrubber!
刷舌工! 刷舌工!
Tongue scrubber! Tongue scrubber!
刷舌工! 刷舌工! 刷舌工! 刷舌工!
Tongue scrubber! Tongue scrubber! Tongue scrubber! Tongue scrubber!
我爸最伟大
My dad was the greatest.
但是,没人会喜欢无名小卒
But nobody loves a nobody.
我想成为大人物
l want to be a somebody.
奥斯卡,你也不一定要 住到礁顶才算个大人物
Oscar , you don't have to live at the top of the reef to be a somebody.
[grunts]
有什么用?如果明天我付不出钱...
What's the difference? lf l don't pay Mr. Sykes back by tomorrow,...
反正一死,所以...
l'm dead anyway, so...
等一下
Wait here.
这是什么?
What's this?
- 粉珍珠? - 嗯
- A pink pearl? - Mm-hm.
哪儿来的?
Where'd you get that?
我祖母给我的
My grandmother gave it to me.
她说从一粒小沙子开始...
She said it started from a tiny grain of sand,
但是过些日子,就会长成美丽的东西
but then, after a while, it grew into something beautiful.
梦想也从小处开始
Dreams can begin small too.
- 不...不...我不能 - 拿去吧
- No. No, l couldn't... - Take it.
这够你还给赛斯的钱
lt'll get you the money you need for Mr. Sykes.
什么意思,你还不懂吗? 我们都说过一千次了
What do you mean, you don't understand? We've been over it 1 ,000 times.
我不想再说一次
l don't want to have to say it again.
你让我很不舒服 我不知道还能怎么说
You're really giving me agita. l don't know how else to say this.
你出去觅食宰了猎物,然后吃了他,就这么简单 谢谢
You see something, you kill it, you eat it. Period. Thanks.
这就是鲨鱼该做的事 是个优良的传统
That's what sharks do. That's a fine tradition.
你是怎么啦?你哥哥法兰克...是个杀手
What's the matter with you? Your brother Frankie, here, he's a killer.
- 谢谢老爸 - 他手脚利落
- Thanks, Pop. - He's beautiful.
他会做该做的事 把嘴擦干净
He does what he's supposed to do. Wipe your face.
但是你...我听说了
But you... l'm hearin' things.
你要明白,如果你懦弱,会让人误认我也软弱
You gotta understand, when you look weak it makes me look weak.
- 我不允许这样 - 我知道,爸,对不起
- l can't have that. - l know, Pop, l'm sorry.
蓝尼,蓝尼,看着我 看着我
Lenny. Lenny. Look at me. Look at me.
这移交的事业是给你,给你们两个
This handin' over the business, it's for you, for both of yous,
你却表现得好像不在乎
and you're acting like you don't even want it.
我必须确认你能胜任
l need to know that you can handle that.
[sighs]
[splutters]
好吧,在我面前,现在,把他吃了
All right. Right here, in front of me now, eat this.
哦...啊...谢谢...老爸
- [whimpers] - Yeah. Gee, thanks, Pop.
跟你说
Here's the thing.
我在节食,我读了一篇关于虾子的文章 他们不利于健康
l'm on a diet. l read an article about these shrimps. They're not good for ya.
你不知道虾子的热量有多高
You know how many calories are in one of those shrimps?
很高
A lot.
没错 没错. 还有...
lt's true. lt's true and the other thing is,
我妹刚生了娃娃 她过世了,只好由我扶养
my sister had a baby and l took it over because she passed away
不幸娃娃的双腿断了
and then the baby lost its legs and its arms
现在已经残废了 不过在我和我太太的悉心照顾下
and now it's nothing but a stump but l still take care of it with my wife
他渐渐长大,也很快乐
and it's growing and it's fairly happy,
但是我们的情况很困难 我得打两份工才能养家
but it's difficult 'cause l've been working a second shift at the factory
to put food on the table,
但当我看着娃娃脸上的充满了爱 那一切都值得了
but all the love l see in that little guy's face makes it worth it in the end.
真实的故事
True story.
- [sobs] - [sighs]
我再说最后一次 我命令你吃了他!
l'm not askin' you anymore. l'm tellin' you. Eat it!
- 不要,发发慈悲吧 - 老爸,拜.
- No. Have mercy. - Pop, please...
- 吃! - 别吃
- Eat! - No eat.
儿子,吃了这只虾子!
Son, eat the shrimp!
不,求你了
No, please.
- 蓝尼,吃吃吃! - 不! 爸!
- Lenny! Eat, eat, eat! - Don't! Pop!
把虾子放下来!
Put the shrimp down!
现在快走,没人看见 从这儿逃出去
Go now. No one's looking. Get out of here.
- 你自由了,快走 - 谢谢
- You're free, now go. - Thank you.
你真是个好人
You're a good person.
大伙儿,咱们走
Come on, fellas.
爸,我一个人能管好礁镇 没问题的
Pop, l can handle the reef. lt's not a problem.
不,一家人得一起干
No. We're gonna do this as a family.
法兰克,我要你带蓝尼去见见市面
Frankie, l want you to take Lenny out, show him the ropes.
- 别这样,老爸 - 你得学做一只鲨鱼
- Come on, Pop. - You're gonna learn how to be a shark.
你喜欢也好,不喜欢也罢
Whether you like it or not.
[bell rings]
[cheering]
那小子最好来,不然就死定了
That kid better show up or he's dead meat.
对,老板,你说的对
Just say the word, boss.
拿着一大袋的钱,去给赛斯先生
Carrying a big ol' envelope full of money, gonna give it to Mr. Sykes.
快快,可别错过千载难逢的机会
Hurry up. This is our chance, we don't want to miss it.
- 你确定吗? - 我一个驯马师朋友给我内幕消息
- You sure? - My trainer friend tipped me off.
输赢都私下安排好了,咱们不会输
The race is rigged. We can't lose.
- 那匹马叫啥? - 幸运日
- What's the horse's name? - Lucky Day.
…幸运日,赔率200比1
[speakers]...Lucky Day, at 200 to 1.
- 我们要发财了! - 发财!
- We're gonna be rich! - Rich!
我马上要住进礁顶啦
Top of the reef, here l come.
不,等等,我在做什么呀?
No, wait. What am l doing?
别忘了安姬说的 别忘了安姬说的
Remember what Angie said. Remember what Angie said.
安姬说啥来着?
What did Angie say?
梦想都从小处出发.
Dreams can begin small.
你只需要,全部下注 全部下注!
You just have to... bet it all. Bet it all!
幸运日赢啦
[commentator] And Lucky Day wins.
[rap music]
五千赌幸运日
Five thousand on Lucky Day to win.
赔率是200比1 赢了就有1百万!
That's 200 to one. That would pay a million clams.
也就是说...这会让我... 奥斯卡...成为百万富翁
Well , l guess that makes me Oscar the millionaire.
百万富翁
[echoes] The millionaire.
幸运日,幸运日
Lucky Day. Lucky Day.
# 她是个危险的尤物 #
She's dangerous, super bad
# 你得当心,她会捞走你的钞票 #
Better watch out, she'll take the cash
# 她是个掏金女郎 # # 她是个掏金女郎 #
She's a gold digger She's a gold digger
# 她是个危险的尤物 #
She's dangerous, super bad
# 你得当心,她会捞走你的钞票 #
Better watch out, she'll take the cash
# 她是个掏金女郎… #
She's a gold digger...
赌的好
Nice bet.
[chuckles]
- 你有名字吗?
- You got a name? - [chuckles]
- 你要告诉我是什么吗?
- You wanna tell me what it is? - [chuckles]
我叫萝拉
Well, mine's Lola.
快,帅哥,快装酷
C'mon, man! Get your game face on!
[yelps]
那个...萝拉, 我叫...
So,... [chuckles] Lola, my name's...
我叫奥斯卡,甜心
My name is Oscar, sweetie.
啊,桑切斯太太
[gasps] Mrs. Sanchez.
我不吃你那套,嘻哈阿谀奉承
The hippity-hop smooth talk don't work with me.
妈的 嗨,刚才...
My bad. Hey, so...
奥斯卡...我还以为你逃了呢
Oscar. l was starting to think you skipped out on me.
赛斯!我路上正看见你去减税柜台呢
Sykes! l see you're already on your way to the concession stand.
你干么?
What are you doing?
可以带杯饮料给我吗? 好极了,谢谢
Mind bringing us back some drinks? That would be great, thanks.
顺便带个热狗给我
And some of them little wiener thingies.
- 你是说那个插根牙签的玩意儿? - 别听他的
- The ones with the toothpicks? - Don't listen to him.
- 来吧,萝拉,我带你去我的包厢 - 你的包厢?
- Let me escort you to... my box. - Your box?!
他的包厢? 你连椅子底下的口香糖都买不起
His box?! You can't even afford the gum under the seats.
他刚下注五千赌幸运儿 我想他什么都买得起
He just laid five grand on Lucky Day. l think he can afford anything he wants.
- 五千?我的五千? - 呃...不...是另外的五千
- Five grand? My five grand?! - No, it was another five grand.
有钱还,却拿去赌了?
You had the money to pay me back and you bet it anyway?
- 等等 - 收据给我!
- Hold up. - Gimme that!
- 很显然我弄错了 - 不不,等等,萝拉
- Clearly l've made a mistake. - No, no, wait! Lola!
内心"深"处,我是很肤"浅"的
Look. Deep down, l'm really superficial.
别误会,我还是认为你很可爱 可你只是个无名小卒
And don't get me wrong, you're cute, but... you're a nobody.
奥斯卡,你很可爱,你只是无名小卒
Oscar, you cute, but you're a nobody.
等等,萝拉,回来
[Ernie] Wait. Lola. Come back.
我不是无名小卒 我是条"热"狗(谐音:赢家)...哈哈
l'm not a nobody. l'm a wiener.
[Ernie and Bernie laugh]
你这家伙也太搞了 全身上下都是麻烦
You are unbelievable. You're in trouble up to your gills
居然还做非分之想 快...快进去
and still you're askin' for more. Now go on, get in here.
奥斯卡,你最好祷告你的马会赢
Oscar, you better pray that this horse of yours comes through.
居然赌了我的五千
Bettin' my five thousand.
喂喂...滚下我的座位 你,滚下我的座位
Hey. Outta my seat. You, outta my seat.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
- 坐稳了,看赛马 - 用你那只好眼睛
- Sit tight and watch the race. - With your good eye.
哈哈...一只好眼睛
[Ernie] Good eye.
赛马就位,他们跑起来了!
[announcer] The horses are at the post. And they're off!
炸鱼条, 然后是海饼干和沙门氏
Fish Fingers, then Seabiscuit and Salmonella.
幸运日似乎出不了闸
Lucky Day seems to be having trouble getting out of the gate.
-  啥? - 只有蠢蛋才赌那匹马
- What? - Only a sucker would bet on that horse.
别紧张 他每次都这样,只是装的
Don't sweat it. He does this all the time. He's playin'.
怎么回事...幸运儿撞出闸
What's this? Lucky Day is now crashing his way through the gate,
现在他加入战局
and he's off and running.
海饼干,炸鱼条...
Seabiscuit, Fish Fingers...
拜托,幸运日,快跑
Please, Lucky Day. Go fast.
过第一道弯,海饼干落后 幸运日却远远殿后
Coming around the turn it's Seabiscuit by a length and Lucky Day well behind.
幸运日加快速度
And here comes Lucky Day,
从后面追上来超过黄尾和沙门氏
coming up from behind, passing Yellow Tail, Salmonella.
你瞧?谁才是你的幸运儿,快呀!
You see? Who's your fish now? Go.
最后一圈 幸运日来了
Around the final turn, here comes Lucky Day.
幸运儿追上炸鱼条了
Lucky Day's now caught up to Fish Fingers.
双方不相上下 幸运日领先
They're head to head. Neck to neck. Lucky Day's ahead.
想想待会儿咱们怎么算钞票,我就觉得累啊
l'm tired just thinkin' about countin' all of this money.
- 看幸运日跑呀 -  我们要
- Look at Lucky Day go. -  We're movin' on up
马上住进东区啦
To the eastside...
难以置信! 今天是幸运日的大日子
[Commentator] Absolutely amazing! This looks to be Lucky Day's big day.
他的幸运日
It's Lucky Day.
[thud]
怎么啦? 幸运日摔倒了
What happened? Lucky Day is down.
我们要住进...东区
We're movin' on up to the east...
不
No.
[rumbling, loud thud]
炸鱼条过来了,紧跟着的是海饼干,黄尾巴
Here's Fish Fingers, followed by Seabiscuit, Yellow Tail...
- 炸鱼条赢了 - 等等,我只是想抱着你
- And Fish Fingers wins. - Wait. l just want to hold you.
不, 放手 让我看看,好吗?
No, Get outta my way. Let me see, will ya?
赛斯,别忘了找乐子的地方
Remember your ''happy place'', Sykes.
难怪大家叫他大赌注
That's why they call him a long shot.
你,简直疯了,对吧? 谁会想到?
Yo, that was crazy, right? Who knew?
我们刚说好,只是个小意外 发财了,一切就绪...
Everything's set, it's a lock, we good to go, we in the money,
他居然在水里摔倒了
and he trips underwater.
看在比目鱼的份上谁会在水里摔跤?
Who in the halibut trips underwater?
- 还有...踩到什么了? - 够了,够了,我受够了
- And by the way, on what? - That's it. That's it, l've had it.
而尼,伯尼 你们去找水里最深的地方
[high-pitched] Ernie. Bernie. Find the deepest hole in the ocean
然后再挖深一点,把他关进去
and when you do, dig deeper. And put him in it.
[wails]
抱歉,孩子,不是我对你有成见 我们只是在商言商
Sorry, kid. lt's nothing personal. lt's just business.
# 别担心 #
Don't worry
# 没啥事 #
About a thing
# 琐事烦恼 #
'Cause every little thing
# 都会过去 #
Is gonna be all right
- 这样唱才对,奥斯卡 - 对呀
- This is how you sing it, Oscar. - Yeah.
赛斯喜欢你,叫我们好好待你
Sykes, he like you, mon. Him say take it easy on you.
- 不过赛斯不在这儿 - 对呀
- But Sykes is not here. [laughs] - True.
而尼,我问你
Ernie, let me ask you a question.
好,问吧
Yeah, mon? Go on.
为什么我们的电可以电人
Why is it that me locks can sting other people,
却对我或者你没效?
but they have no effect on me or you?
- [zap] - [screams]
而尼,我不是故意的,而尼 而尼,我不是故意的,老兄!
Ernie. l didn't mean it, Ernie. l didn't mean it, man. Ernie.
[laughs]
噢,而尼,你在开玩笑 开的好,老兄,崇拜...
Ernie, you made a joke. Good one, man. Respect.
大开杀戒
Bloodfire.
法兰奇,你明知道我不能
[Lenny] Frankie, you know l can't do this.
蓝尼,如果想要让老爸高兴,你就得杀生
[Frankie] lf you wanna make Pop happy, you've gotta kill something.
或许我去找条很老的病鱼 在他旁边等就成了
[Lenny] Or, l could find an old, sick fish and just wait.
你在餐厅里的事已经传开了
[Frankie] lt's gettin' around, your thing at the restaurant.
你知道鱼言可畏
You know how fish talk.
这个,那个,另一个,你好吗? 碰一声,忘了吧,你是个死人了
This, that, the other. How you doin'? Boom. Forget it, you're dead.
说正格儿的,我不太懂你这聪明人的话 你得讲清楚一点
Okay, seriously, l can't understand wise guy so be more specific.
清楚! 你要我讲清楚! 这辈子起码做一次真正的鲨鱼吧!
Specific? You want specific? Be a shark for once in your life.
- 啊～我该怎么办? - 蓝尼,算了吧
- What am l gonna do? - Lenny, forget about it, okay?
咱们一起干几回儿 乒乒乓乓一阵,老爸高兴了
We do a couple of practice runs, badda-bing badda-boom, Pop's happy,
你成了真正的鲨鱼, 咱们还继续过日子,懂吗?
you're a shark, life goes on. Capiche?
好吧...懂了.
Okay. Okay, capiche.
成啦
Bingo.
就在那儿,看到了吧 电视快餐,没比这更简单的了
Right there. Dead ahead. You see it? TV dinner. Don't get easier than this.
好吧,来,我是猛虎
All right. Come on. Eye of the tiger.
法兰克,我能行 如果还是不行呢?
Frankie, l can do this. What if l can't do this?
- 那也别回家了 - 说的好,好吧
- Then don't bother comin' home. - Good point. All right.
再电他尾巴一次
Hit him in the tail again.
- 我喜欢看他滑稽表情 - 对呀
- l like the funny face he make. - Yeah.
- 而尼 - 快逃!
- Ernie. - Blow out.
[muffled shouts]
哥们,哥们,别丢下我不管呀
Guys? Guys? Don't leave me alone.
搞不好,就有只鲨鱼来了
Come on, there could be sharks out here.
[screams]
别...等等...对不起 不不不,我不会…
Oh, no. Wait. l'm sorry. No, no, no. l'm not gonna...
- 蓝尼,像这样 - 什么?
- Lenny. Like this. - What?
哦,不要
[Lenny] Oh, no.
[Lenny groans]
你就干脆点儿吧
Just get it over with.
等等,等等,帮个忙,别咀嚼
Wait a minute. Do me a favor, don't chew me.
- 嚼我的口感不好 - 我不会吃你
- l'm not for that. - l'm not gonna eat you.
少来,别跟我装傻
Don't do the whole head trip thing with me.
听好... 我没说之前,你别动
Listen to me. Don't move until l tell you.
啊啊啊!退后
- [growls] - Ahhh! Back up.
对啦,就这样,蓝尼,好好享受吧
That's it, Len. There you go, buddy.
就这样, 摆动鱼翅 钻进去
That's it. Wave those fins, baby. Dig in.
看,我假装吃你,好让你逃
[snarls] Look, l'm just pretending so you can get away.
现在,等我转过身,你就快逃
Now, when l turn around, you take off.
吃起来像炸鸡
Tastes just like chicken.
嗯...嗯…
Mmm. Mmm.
哦,不
Oh, no.
- 我刚对你说啥来着? - 哦,对不起,我没办法
- What did l tell you? - l'm sorry, l didn't get it.
- 你要我现在就走? - 快逃呀
- You want me to go now? - Just go.
够了,我受不了啦.
That's it. l've had it up to here.
[snarls]
- 哦,不 - 快...快逃
- Oh, no. - Hurry, swim.
- 不,法兰克,等等 - 不要...快拉住他...快拉住他!
- No, Frankie, wait. - No! Get your boy, get your boy!
- [clang] - [thudding]
[distant rumbling]
法兰克
[gasps] Frankie.
蓝尼?
- [thud] - [Frankie] Lenny?
[coughs]
- 蓝尼,是你吗? - 是我,法兰克
- Lenny, is that you? - l'm here, Frankie.
- 靠近点儿 - 是...你想说什么?
- Come closer. - Yes, what is it?
我好冷
l'm so cold.
这只是因为我们是冷血动物
That's just because we're cold-blooded.
- 噢! - 蠢蛋
- Ow! - Moron.
法兰克...不要…
Frankie, no...
不要!
[wails] No!
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
我对不起你,法兰克
l'm so sorry, Frankie.
我怎么向爸解释?
How am l ever going to explain this to Pop?
噢,不
- [sobs] Oh, no. - [Oscar squeaks]
[shrieks]
退后, 我疯了,我功夫了得...
Back up. l'm crazy. l be trippin'.
- 哇哦!
- [makes kung fu noises] - Whoa!
妈的...
What the...
- [shrieks] - [both shriek]
别伤害我们,对不起 都是而尼的主意
Don't hurt us. We're sorry. lt was all Ernie's idea.
奥斯卡,是你杀了那只鲨鱼?
Oscar. Did you kill that shark?
嗯...对
Uh... yeah.
看起来是我,就是我
Exactly how it look, that's how it is.
发生啥事了?
What happened?
你...你想知道怎么回事?
You wanna know what happened?
是啊,你站在一只鲨鱼的身上
Yeah. You're standing on top of a shark.
说吧,伙计
Go on, man.
让我告诉你怎么回事...
Well, l'll tell you what happened.
大鲨鱼,75-100寸长
Big ol' shark, about 75, 1 00-feet long.
- 他正向我游过来,对吧?
- So he's swimming at me, right? - [crowd gasp]
- 牙齿像利刃 - 利刃,哈
- With teeth like razors. - Razors.
我就...像这样,你敢这样过来?
And l was, like, you're gonna come at me like that?
你敢就这样走向我"奥"?
You're gonna come at the ''O'' like that?
喂～秀你的肌肉...肌肉
Do the muscle thing, the muscle thing.
哦...对对对
Oh, right.
我跟那小子说 你看到这家伙了吗? 然后像这样指给他看
So l told that dude, ''You see this guy?'' and l pointed like this.
你还有个兄弟,就住在那边
Well, he's got a brother. And he lives right over here.
我想现在是兄弟团聚的时候了
And l think it's time for a little family reunion.
- [laughs] - [crowd cheer]
老弟,跟你说过了吧 我们就在那儿
You see, mon. l told you. We were right there.
借过
[lady fish] Pardon me.
- 让开! - 噢,对不起
- Move it! - Oh. Sorry.
- 她在电视上看起来很和善 - 奥斯卡,我是凯蒂・辛文
- She seems so nice on TV. - Oscar, Katie Current.
你是历史上第一个赢了鲨鱼的人 告诉我
As the first fish in history to ever take on a shark and win, tell me:
这是不是表示,以后你就是礁镇的守护者? 镇上的警长?
Does this mean you're now protector of the reef, new sheriff in town?
凯蒂,不瞒你说
Katie, l'm gonna keep it real.
- 我可以叫你凯蒂吧? - 当然
- l can call you Katie? - Of course.
任何鲨鱼想来奥斯卡的地盘捣蛋 就一定会完蛋
Any shark try to mess around in Oscartown is goin' down.
[roaring]
还押韵,我还是个诗人哩
Yeah, it's poetic. In the heat I get poetic.
奥斯卡,嗯嗯…
Oscar. Hmm.
奥斯卡
Oscar.
让开,无名小梭鱼 任何的问题都得经过我
Get out of here, you barracudas. Any further questions will be fielded by me.
- 那你是? - 我是他的经纪人
- And you are? - l'm his manager.
- 赛斯,斯文的斯 - 我是他的财务顾问
- Sykes, with a ''y''. - And l'm his financial advisor.
想看我的玩偶吗?
You want to see my puppets?
哈
[raspy voice] Hello.
对不起,请大家等我们一下
Could you excuse us for a moment, please?
- 我的经纪人? - 小子,你是大腕了
- My manager? - Kid, you're a superstar.
- 我们要发财了,以后一切交给我 - 那五千块怎么办?
- We're gonna make a fortune. - What about the 5 G's?
还提那五千干嘛 以后咱们就是合伙人了
Forget the 5 G's. We're partners now.
- 我们到底在谈什么? - 我想九一分帐?
- So what are we talking about? - l'm thinkin' 90-1 0 split?
- 你还满大方的 - 你一成,我九成,你还多赚了呢
- That's generous. - You're the 1 0, l'm 90.
- 这可不行 - 那你说呢
- l don't think so. - Talk to me.
- 你拿一成五 -七成
- You get 1 5. - 70.
- 两成 - 七成五
- 20. - 75.
老兄,你走错方向了
Dude, you're goin' the wrong way.
五五分? 五五分?
50-50.
- 你满意了吗? - 不,你呢?
- You happy? - No. You?
- 不 - 成交
- No. - Deal.
我和我经纪人现在开始回答问题
My manager and l are now prepared to take your questions.
奥斯卡,你以后还会在洗车厂工作吗?
Oscar, are you going to continue working here at the Wash?
拜,我才刚走马上任
Please, l barely work here now.
继续啊,小伙子,你要杀了他们了
Keep it up, kid. You're slayin' 'em.
不,他杀的是鲨鱼
No. He's slayin' sharks.
嘿,好极了 说的好,我喜欢
Hey, that's good. That's good, l like that.
奥斯卡..."屠鲨者"
Oscar the Sharkslayer.
哇...屠鲨者!
Whoa! A sharkslayer.
大家刚从本台听到
[Katie] You heard it here first.
以后鲨鱼还敢来捣乱 这就是他葬身之地
From now on, any shark tries to bother this reef, it's his funeral.
(法文哀悼辞)
[shark] Nomine Patri, et Filii, et Spiritus Sancti.
# 我能飞的比老鹰还高 #
I could fly higher than an eagle
# 如果你是我翅膀下的风 #
If you are the wind beneath my wings
[coughs]
- 法兰克,我们会想念你 - 敬悼法兰克
- Frankie, we'll miss you. - [All] To Frankie.
真不幸,唐・李诺 每个人都喜欢法兰克
lt's a terrible thing, Don Lino. Everybody loved Frankie.
愿凶手千倍偿还
May whoever did this die a thousand deaths.
愿他腐臭生蛆的尸体 在地狱炼火中灰飞湮灭
May his stinking, maggot-covered corpse rot in the fiery depths of hell.
谢谢你的仁慈,狄先生
Thank you for your kind thoughts, Giuseppe.
哦,也希望蓝尼一切平安,希望他都好
Oh, and may Lenny be found safe and sound too. Hope he's okay.
哦,蓝尼
Oh, Lenny...
- 别担心,老板 - 我才说了他一顿
- Don't worry, boss. - l said some things to him...
得去找他才是
We gotta find him.
到处都找过了,别放在心上 他会自己回来的
We're searching everywhere. Forget about it, he'll turn up.
那孩子到底怎么了? 为什么他总是与众不同?
What's wrong with that kid? Why's he gotta be so different?
法兰克,上帝保佑他的灵魂 他是那么完美,那么完美
Frankie, God rest his soul, he was perfect. Perfect.
哦,路卡,到底是谁干的?
Oh... Luca. Who could have done this?
唐・李诺,在这最困难的时候
[clears throat] Don Lino, at this most difficult time,
请接受我最深切的哀悼
please accept my deepest condolences.
谢谢你,唐・菲伯,为我儿子唱挽歌
Thank you, Don Feinberg, for honoring my son with your song.
我得到些关于是谁杀了法兰克的消息
l got some news, about the guy who took out Frankie.
- [breaks wind] - [bubbling]
我们…嗯…到那边谈
Let's... Yeah, let's talk over here.
这家伙不知打哪儿来的
He come out of nowhere, this guy.
自称为"屠鲨者"
Calls himself ''The Sharkslayer''.
我在这儿呢
[clears throat] lra, over here.
- 对不起,"屠鲨者" - 我去哪里找他
- Sorry. ''The Sharkslayer''. - Where do l find him?
他住在南礁市,这是我们唯一知道的
He's from the Southside Reef. That's all we could dig up.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 有人点歌吗? - 路卡
- Any requests? - Luca.
那我来唱铁达尼号主题曲? 不要
- [Don Feinberg] That Titanic song? - [other sharks] No.
叫赛斯来 他对礁镇比谁都熟
Get Sykes. He knows that reef better than anybody.
我要找到他,知道他一切
l wanna find this guy. l wanna know about him,
住哪? 睡哪?
where he lives, where he sleeps.
他如果杀人,我也要知道 谁是屠鲨者
He pops a gill? l wanna know about it. Who is this Sharkslayer?
他来了...屠鲨者
[male fish] Here he is. The Sharkslayer.
[ Mary J. Blige: Got To Be Real]
# 我想爱你,宝贝 # # 你现在感觉到什么 #
-  I think I love you, baby -  What you feel now
# 我需要你,宝贝 # # 你现在知道什么 #
-  I think I need you, baby -  What you know now
# 嗯,嗯 # # 美梦成真 #
-  Uh-huh -  To be real
# 噢噢噢 #
Oooh
# 你的爱已成真 #
Your love's for real now
# 你知道你的爱 #
- [elevator dings] -  You know that your love
# 和我的爱,我的爱就在这里 #
And my love My love is here to stay
派对现在正式开始
Let's get this party started right.
[scratching]
他在这儿...大"奥"...
There he is, the big O.
- 赛斯 - 击重点儿,重点儿
- Sykes. - Pound that dog. Pound it.
奥斯卡,保护礁镇,保护礁镇,老兄
Oscar, raise the reef. Raise the reef, buddy.
- 嗯... - 哦,是啊,热门人物
- Uh, yeah... - Oh, yeah. Hot.
说的好
Yeah, that's pretty...
来跳卷心菜舞...卷心菜舞
Come on, cabbage patch. Cabbage patch.
- 安姬,你总算来了 - 别急,我怕你打破我的礼物
- Angie, you made it. - Wait, you're gonna break my gift.
别,别,你不需要带礼物 你给我啥?
Come on. You didn't have to get me anything. What'd you get me?
每个单身汉都需要什么?
What does every bachelor pad need?
岩浆灯? 你怎么知道我喜欢岩浆灯?
A lava lamp? How did you know l love lava lamps?
那...我就把它放在 我另一盏灯的旁边
You know what, l'm gonna put it right here next to my other one.
喂...安姬,快过来 我带你看这里最棒的东西
Hey, come on, Ang. l wanna show you the best thing about this place.
- 景色如何? - 礁...顶...真棒呀!
- How great is this view? - Top of the reef. lt's amazing.
- 对呀,漂亮极了,对吧? - 像你...
- l know. lt's beautiful, right? - Like you...
像你...你的...新套房 真是...哇...棒极了!
Like you... your new apartment. lt's... wow. Awesome.
我其实想说的是...我为你感到骄傲
What l'm trying to say is that l'm proud of you.
嗯...是...其实也没什么啦
Yeah. lt was nothing, really, you know.
哦,就在这儿,等着别动哦
Hey... Hey, oh, you know what, wait right here. Don't move.
我马上回来 小姐,你一定会手舞足蹈
l'll be right back. Girl, you are gonna flip.
- 噗...我回来了 - 噢,...你回来了
- l'm back. - You're back.
你知道吗,安姬?
You know what, Ang?
我现在住的地方...我崭新的生活
Where l am right now, this whole new life l got...
我的梦想成真
All my dreams comin' true...
我还有点莫名其妙
ln a weird kinda way...
没有你,我绝不会成功
Well, l never could've done it without you.
你当然能
Oh, sure you could.
也或许不能
Well, probably not. [chuckles]
安姬...呃...给
Ang. Here.
噢...奥斯卡
Oh! Oscar!
我知道,我知道 对不起让你等这么久
l know. l know. l'm just sorry that it took so long.
没事,没事
That's okay.
砰!嗯?
Bam! Huh?
我祖母的珍珠
My grandmother's pearl.
再加上利息 我从不忘事儿
With interest. Now, l don't forget anything,
- 更不会忘了我的朋友 - 哦!
- and l never forget who my friends are. - Oh!
[both chuckle]
安姬...我...
Ang, l...
呃...嗨
[Lola] Oh, hi.
我没打扰你们吧?
l'm not interrupting something, am l?
- 是的,我们正在谈话 - 没有没有
- Yes, we're talking. - No.
萝拉...哇...你来啦
Hey, Lola. Wow. You're here.
- 哦
- [clears throat] - Oh.
喔,给你介绍,这是我最好的朋友安姬...
You, er, you gotta come best my meet friend, Angie.
我最安的好姬...我姬的好安...
Uh, uh, eat my best men, Wangie...
最好的朋友?哦,真好
Your best friend? Oh, that's sweet.
你不介意,我借你的朋友一会儿吧?
So you won't mind if l steal him for a while, will you?
[music plays in background]
瞧...看看谁最终是个大人物
So, look who's a somebody after all.
- 哦...你知道 - 鲨鱼!
- Well, you know... - [male fish] Sharks!
就在市郊附近! 大...白...鲨!
On the... on the edge of the reef! Th.. Th... They're great whites!
鲨鱼 快...大家快回家
Sharks. Okay, everybody go home to your loved ones,
陪你的爱人渡过最后几小时
spend the last few hours that you have with each other.
哦...
Oh...
我的意思是说...
l mean...
以前才需要这样
That's the way it used to be around here.
我们大家乱成一团,找地方躲起来
We'd have been all scrambling for cover and stuff,
- 但...现在奥斯卡来了
- but not since Oscar came to town. - [cheering]
萝拉...宝贝,在这儿等我 我处理完鲨鱼后马上回来
So, Lola, baby, just wait here and l'm gonna be right back.
我去教训鲨鱼了
l'm gonna go take care of these sharks.
- 给他们点颜色,猛虎 - 二头肌,三角肌,呵呵
- Go get 'em, tiger. - Woo! Biceps, triceps.
[laughs, growls]
- 帅,奥斯卡 - 就看你的了,奥斯卡
- All right, Oscar. - Go get 'em, Oscar.
- [growls] - [whistling]
[Oscar sobs and wails]
蓝尼
[shark] Lenny.
妈的,躲到哪儿了?蓝尼
Where the heck is he? Lenny!
你在干嘛?
Hey. What are you doin'?
小心屠鲨者! 你不想活啦!
There's a sharkslayer out here. You wanna be next?
对哦
Oh, yeah...
蓝尼...蓝尼...
[whispers] Lenny? Lenny?
好险 真的非常险
- [sighs with relief] That was close. - [Lenny] Super close.
别慌
Don't panic.
[muffled scream]
别叫,我们很安全
Quiet. We're safe.
- 怎么又是你 - 嗯
- Oh, no, not you again. - Yeah.
- 谁在那里!!! - 哇～你搞什么鬼呀!
- Ah! What was that?! - Yo! What is with you, man?
- 嘘～他可能就在附近 - 谁?
- Shh! He could be anywhere. - Who?
嘘～屠鲨者
Shh! The Sharkslayer.
- 哪来什么屠鲨者 - 呵呵～有,当然有
- There's no sharkslayer out here. - [chuckles] Yes, there is.
呵呵～没,当然没 我保证没有
[mimics chuckle] No, there is not. Trust me on this one.
你清醒点好吗! 什么时候了还装疯卖傻
Get a hold of yourself, man. This is no time to act crazy.
你才装疯卖傻哩,疯子
You the one acting crazy, crazy.
对,你说的对,对不起 最近我不知怎么搞,自从...
[sighs] You're right. l'm sorry. l haven't been myself since the...
唔...
the, uh,...
别哭
Don't cry.
[cries in anguish]
别,那事别放心上,放松
No, no, it's not all that. Just relax.
都是我的错……其实……不 不过还是我的错
lt's my fault... kinda... not really... but still. My brother...
老兄...别... 再过些时候就会没事的
You just need a little time, man. Look, things'll work out.
- 真的吗? - 当然
- You think? - Yeah.
呃...我要走了
So, look, l'm gonna take off...
你也该回家了,好吗?
And you should just go home, okay?
- 好 - 祝你好运,老兄
- Okay. - Hey, good luck, dawg.
- 等等 - 又怎么啦?
- Wait. - What, man?
- 还不知道你的名字 - 奥斯卡
- l didn't catch your name. - Oscar.
- 我是蓝尼,嗨 - 嗨
- l'm Lenny. Hi. - Hi.
你...你...住哪儿?
Where do you live?
蓝尼...在我住的地方 鱼儿可不喜欢被鲨鱼捏在手里
Lenny, where l come from, fish don't like to get grabbed by sharks.
- 对不起 - 回家去
- Sorry. - Go home.
我无家可归...你难道不懂吗?
There is no home for me now. Don't you understand?
- 你这么大个儿,捏的我很难过 - 带我回家
- You too big to be grabbing on me. - Take me home with you.
没人会知道我在你家 我就像只隐形的鲨鱼
You won't even notice l'm there. l'm like the invisible shark.
你疯啦
Are you crazy?
求求你,带我回家,别丢下我不管
[sobs] Please. l'm begging you. Don't leave me alone.
喂...把手举起来靠着墙让我看见
[kid] Put your fins on the wall where l can see 'em.
- 吓着你了吧 - 哦...孩子们
- Gotcha. - Hey. Yo, The Shorties.
- 奥斯卡 - 你们在这儿干嘛?
- Oscar. - What y'all doin' here?
- 干点疯狂的事 - 噢,就是这个
- Check out my mad burner. - [all] Whoop, there it is.
怎么样啊?
How ya like that?
呵...你们还满有天份的嘛
Hey, y'all kids got some skills.
野性画风,老兄
lt's wild style, doo.
不是告诉过你们吗? 小孩不准涂鸦
What did l tell you? You kids shouldn't be doin' this.
还有...这么晚了外面不安全
And besides, it's not safe to be out here at night.
现在很安全啦,因为你是屠鲨者
lt is now, bro-bro. You the Sharkslayer.
对呀
Yeah, bro-bro.
- 屠鲨者? - 谁在说话?
- Sharkslayer? - What was that?
有时我没事也会咳嗽
[coughs loudly] Sometimes l be coughin' for nothin'.
听着,你们不能街上晃荡,我说真的
l need you off these streets, seriously.
回家去,我认识你们妈妈 我会告诉说你们在干坏事
Get your butts home. l'll tell your moms y'all doin' bad stuff.
- 咱们去让赛斯变气球 - 好哇
- Let's go make Mr. Sykes puff up. - Yeah.
- 拜拜,奥斯卡 - 待会儿见,老兄
- Bye, Oscar. - [kid] See ya later, doo.
蓝尼,刚才你看到了吗?
Lenny. Did you see what just happened there?
我知道啊 他们还以为你是屠鲨者咧,哈哈
l know. [laughing] They think you're the Sharkslayer.
就像是
As if. [cackles]
我不喜欢你的酸调儿
l don't appreciate your funky tone, actually.
别...等等...对不起,说正格儿的
No, wait up. Hey. l'm sorry, seriously.
你别生我的气
l don't want you mad at me,
更别..."屠"了我,哈哈
and l certainly don't want you to [sniggers] slay me.
你很高兴嘛 自得其乐啊
You're having a good time? You're enjoying yourself?
告诉你吧,我就是屠鲨者
Well, for your information, l am the Sharkslayer.
屠鲨者奥斯卡 大家都这么说
Oscar the Sharkslayer. That's what people be sayin'.
- 等等,真是你? - 嗯
- Wait. You mean, you... - Yeah.
当那个船锚...
When the anchor...
你是大骗子
[gasps] Oh, you're a liar.
我...才没...说谎 就算我说谎
Hey, l didn't lie, all right? All right, l lied.
只是个小谎,不伤大雅的
But it was a little lie. Come on, who's it gonna hurt anyway?
我跟你说这干嘛
Man, l'm not explaining myself to you.
- 你管自个儿的事吧 - 没问题
- You're on your own. - No problem.
假如...老天有眼...有人...
And if, God forbid, someone should, l don't know,
呃...在我回家的路上 发现事实的真相
find out the truth about the Sharkslayer on my way back...
- 你敢! - 我当然敢!
- You wouldn't. - l would.
唔…
Uh... [tuts, sighs] Tssk!
快过来 你当然能跟我回家
Come here. Of course you can come with me.
但...你也知道... 你是鲨鱼,对吧?
But, you know, you're a shark, right?
我是屠鲨者 我们在一起不能被人看到
And l'm a Sharkslayer, so we can't be seen together.
- 你会钻洞吧? - 钻啊...扒呀...
- You dig, dog? - Dig. Dog.
钻啊...扒呀... 对呀,我是扒洞狗
Dog dig. Dig dog. Yeah, yo diggy dog.
你就快点吧!
Just come on.
听好蓝尼,紧紧跟着我 不准出一点儿声
OK, Lenny, follow my every move and don't make a sound.
没问题
You got it.
有回声 唉哦...哦..哦
Ooh, an echo. Echo. [echoes]
现在防卫南边的鲨鱼…
Now batting for the Southside Sharks...
噢,不可以打人
- [smacking] - [Lenny] Ow! lt's not okay to hit.
- [smacking]
噢,不可以打人
[siren]
- 噢~ - 嘘!
- Ooh-ee - Shh!
- [thud] - [Lenny yelps]
噢!
Ow!
- [shrieks] - [crashing]
- 快把你的大屁股弄进去 - 你想会不会有人听到?
- Get your tail in there. - Do you think anybody heard that?
谁呀? 是谁在外面? 嘿,到底是谁在外面?
Who was that? Who? Hey. Who's out there?
呦～老疯乔
Yo. Crazy Joe.
我就说嘛,我是听声音了 你把那只鲨鱼解决了?
l thought l heard something. Did you get that shark?
你想都想不到...乔
You have no idea, Joe.
了不得! 得走了,节目开始了
That's great. Well, gotta go. My show's on.
[ Theme From The Benny Hill Show]
[Crazy Joe laughs]
好了,安全了 起码目前为止
All right. We're safe. For now.
哇～
Ahh.
有床
Hey, a bed.
哦...好极了... 天堂般...软绵绵舒服极了
Oh, yeah, that's good. That's heaven, yeah.
抱呀…挤呀…
Snuggly, buggly, wuggly.
我爱死你了,老兄
l love you, man.
- 哇,住手 - 你是我的新朋友
- Whoa. Hold up. - You're my new best friend.
停
Stop it.
你要做朋友?也行...
OK, you wanna be friends? Fine.
但是得有规矩 第一
But we gotta lay down some rules. Rule number one:
不能...抱呀挤呀...像刚那样
No snuggly, buggly... Whatever that just was.
没问题,还有呢?
You got it. Anything else?
第二,也是最重要的
Rule number two, and this is the most important rule.
如果,万一,假如...你饿了
ln the event that possibly you get hungry...
别担心,我不会吃谁的
Don't worry, l won't eat anyone.
如果你还没注意到... 我和其他鲨鱼不同
lf you haven't noticed, l'm different from other sharks.
就这样,不用再提了,晚安
Let's put it that way, leave it at that. Good night.
- 什么不同? - 你会嘲笑我
- Define ''different''. - You'll laugh.
我不会
l'm not gonna laugh.
说说罢了,待会儿你就会
That's what you say, and then what happens? You laugh.
蓝尼,我保证
Lenny, l give you my word.
好吧,我告诉你
Okay, l will tell you.
我是...我是吃素的
l'm... l'm a vegetarian.
等等
[stifles laugh] Hold up.
- 就这样? - 就这样是啥意思?
- So that's it? - Tch! What do you mean, that's it?
你是第一个我告诉的人 保密好累人
You're the first fish l ever told. l'm tired of keeping it a secret.
我爸爸...他不能接受我这个样子
And my dad, he'll never accept me for who l am.
我倒底是怎么了?
What's wrong with me?
你很正常,老兄
Nothin' is wrong with you, man.
我认为,所有的鲨鱼都该像你一样
l think all sharks should be like you.
天,你真会安慰我
God, that's sweet of you to say.
不要在怪自己啦
And stop blaming yourself for what happened.
真的?
Really?
如果真要怪,就怪我好了
lf you wanna blame anybody, blame me.
如果我没去那里,就不会发生了
lf l hadn't been there in the first place, none of this would've happened.
对呀,如果老爸知道真相 他肯定不会饶了你
Jeez, if Pop knew that, he'd ice you for sure.
饶!?...呵...难道他是黑帮教父?
''lce''. What's he, the Godfather or something?
- 对 - 啥意思?
- Yeah. - Whatcha mean, ''yeah''?
- 他是
- Yeah, he is. - [gulps]
你没事儿吧?
Hey. Are you all right?
[screams]
- [laughs] - [bleeping]
- 我都说过啦 - 我有照做呀
- Man. l told ya. - l'm doing it.
先按Ｘ,再按Ｏ,然后↓↓,再□□
X, circle, X X, double left square, right trigger, down, square, square.
- 喔,按两次□□ - 还真的哩!
- Double square. Respect. - Respect.
告诉你件新鲜事吧 屠鲨者聘我做经纪
l've got news for you. The Sharkslayer made me his manager.
所以说你动不了我的 听到了吧
So l'm now, what l like to call, untouchable. You hear me?
- 赛斯 - 嗨,奥斯卡
- Sykes. - Hey, Oscar.
哦!嘿!...赛斯?
Oh! Hey!... Sykes?
嗨嗨,兄弟,伙伴,我的屠鲨者
Hey, there he is. My brotha, my player, the Sharkslayer.
- 行了,听着... - 从现在你得付我保护费
- Whatever. Listen... - Now you'll have to pay me protection.
赛斯,解除合约 我杀的人是唐・李诺的儿子
Sykes. The deal is off. That shark l killed was Don Lino's son.
- 我知道,又如何? - 如何? 万一他知道了
- l know. Ain't it great? - Not if he finds out.
知道又如何,我现正在和他讲电话
What do you mean? He's on the phone right now.
对,屠鲨者现在就在我面前
That's right, l got the Sharkslayer right here in front of me.
他会宰了你,再宰了所有你的手下
And he's gonna slay you and all your sharks.
赛斯,闭嘴...闭...嘴!
Sykes, shut up! Shut up!
好...说的好...我喜欢
Hey, that's good, l like that.
- 闭嘴,李诺...闭嘴
- Shut up, Lino. Shut up. - [Oscar sighs]
- 啥? 他要和你说话 - 我不在这儿,不在这儿
- What? Kid, he wants to talk to you. - No. l'm not here.
对,他就在这儿
Yeah, he's right here.
- 哈 - 闭嘴? 你要我闭嘴?
- [gently] Hello. - Shut up? Shut up?
- 我要你闭嘴才是
- You don't tell me ''shut up''. - [beeping on line]
- 哈? - 你好吗?
- Hello? - How you doin'?
我要一个披萨 加上所有的料...鱼,肉丸,蘑菇
Give me a pie with everything on it. Anchovies, meatballs...
- 路卡 - 嗨,老板
- Luca. - Hi, Boss.
- 你怎么跑去批萨店打工? - 挂...电...话!
- Why you working in a pizza joint? - Get off the phone!
- 但是我饿了
- But l'm hungry. - [sighs]
我的手下会来教训你,屠鲨者
My guys are coming for you, Sharkslayer.
把你身上的鳞一片一片扒下来
They're gonna tear you fin from fin.
现在知道谁是你干爸了吧? 我一定会照顾你的,对吧?
Come on, who's your puff daddy? Who takes care of you?
你们两个,去办差
Come on, you two, we got work to do.
- 噢,我马上要赢了说 - 赛斯,你误会了
- Mon, l was winning. - Sykes. You got it all wrong.
他们替你谱了首歌
They'll write songs about you.
# 鲨鱼,满嘴牙 #
Oh, the shark bites
- 赛斯 # 咬一口... #
- Sykes. -  With his teeth, dear
- 唱吧 # 突然奥斯卡... #
- Sing it, mon. -  And then Oscar
# 痛扁他们 #
Kicked his butt
赛斯,老兄
Sykes, man!
- 别这样 - 或许我能帮你
- Come on. - [Lola] Maybe l can help.
嗨,萝拉 你在这儿干嘛
Hey. Lola? What're you doing here?
你常常突然就出现了
You just be poppin' up, sometimes, places.
- 你叫我等的呀,所以...
- Well, you said to wait, so... [claps] - [sexy music starts]
我一直在等
l've been waiting.
我...真的没时间
[laughs nervously] Look, l don't have a lot of time
拍手,关灯
for the hand-clappy makin'-the-lights-go-off
音乐...共度良宵
music-playing-in-the-dark thing.
- 你怕什么? - 怕! 哈哈
- What are you afraid of? - Afraid... [laughs]
好笑,我怎么会怕! 只是...呜哇
Yeah, that's funny. l ain't afraid of nothin', it's just... Ooh.
宝贝,你太紧张了
Oh, baby, you are so tense.
对呀,最近工作压力大 得保护礁镇
Yeah, l've been stressed lately, you know, protecting the reef.
就我一人,实在...
l do that by myself, you know.
- 太要命了 - 工作太重,过度劳累
- lt's just crazy. - lt's too much, it's piling up...
对呀,一个案子接着一个
Yeah, you know, one thing on top of the other.
我正考虑要退休了
Actually, l was thinking about retiring.
- 你不想退休 - 我不想?
- You don't want to do that. - l don't?
你的最高成就得来不易
You have worked your way to the top.
你不想再做个人下人,是吗?
You don't want to go back to the bottom, do you?
当然不
No.
不
决不
No way.
你只要给他们点儿颜色 那些鲨鱼就不敢接近你
You just show 'em who's boss and those sharks will leave you alone.
对,你说的对 蓝尼
Yeah, you're right. [aside] Lenny.
[handle clicks, creaking]
噗嘶!
Psst!
蓝尼?你在哪儿?
Lenny? Where are you?
哈,奥斯卡
Hello, Oscar.
安姬,嘿,你怎么会这儿?
Angie. Hey, what are you doing here?
怎么啦? 你忘了东西?
What, did you forget something?
或许你忘了...你的鲨鱼
Oh, maybe you forgot your shark.
[slurping]
嗨
Hi.
鲨鱼! 安姬我掩护你
Uh... Shark! Swim, Angie, l'll cover you.
快,不然就来不及了 你一个人先回去
Quick, before it's too late. Go on without me.
少来啦,你的宠物鲨把真相都告诉我了
Oh, stop it. Your pet shark here told me everything.
啥! 蓝尼,你为什么要说?
Dang, Lenny, why would you do that?
我...我也不知道...我喜欢她
l don't know... l like her.
谢谢,我也喜欢你
Thank you. l like you, too.
你头壳坏啦,怎么把他带来了
What were you thinking, bringing him in here?
我...只是暂时...我再想法解决
No, l'm still working out the kinks.
解决! 你撒谎
Kinks? You lied.
大家都以为 你真的宰了鲨鱼
Everybody thinks you slayed the shark.
- 我怎么能说大家都错了呢? - 你怎能骗我呢!? 骗"我"啊!
- Who am l to tell them they're wrong? - How could you lie to me? Me!
不是针对你一人 得了,我是骗了所有的人
Don't take it personally. Come on, l lied to everybody.
好吧,对不起,算我错了 我是真的骗了你
All right, look, l'm sorry. l totally betrayed you,
但听着...我只有一个小问题,还待解决
but listen, l got just one little problem l gotta take care of.
- 又是什么问题? - 鲨鱼黑帮份子会来找我!
- Oh, what's that? - Sharks are coming to get me!
他们会的 我的意思是,你活该
And they should. l mean, what'd you expect?
你以为宰了一只鲨鱼
You'd take credit for killing a shark,
你下半辈子还能平安过日子?
and then everything would be fine and dandy for the rest of your life?
呃...对呀
Uh... yeah.
但...别担心...没事的
But, hey, don't you worry about it.
蓝尼和我,我们可以解决问题
Me and Lenny got it. We gonna fix it.
"我们"是啥意思? 可别把我也拖下水
''We''? l don't want any part of this.
现在说太晚了,吃素的 他们也会来找你
Too late, veggie-boy. They're lookin' for you, too.
说的也是...现在怎么办?
Point taken. What's the plan?
- 好...咱们就这样... - 奥斯卡,我有个主意
- This is what we gonna do. - [Angie] Here's the plan.
你说出真相 你呢...回家
You tell the truth. And, you, go home.
[both laugh]
好吧,听好,咱们这么干
All right, look, this is what we're gonna do.
我用红油漆把你涂的血淋淋
We're gonna paint you up all bloody. A mess, right?
然后在鲨鱼来之前,去堵住他们
Then you gonna swim out and meet the sharks before they get here.
你就说,停! 不要再往前走了
And you're gonna say, ''Stop. Don't y'all. Don't go no farther!''
那个屠鲨者跟疯了一样
''That Sharkslayer's crazy, man!''
把我打的浑身是伤 简直是个冷血杀手
''He beat me senseless. He's a stone-cold killer, man!''
然后你就说我很壮 还有我很帅,就这么说
Then you could tell 'em l'm huge. Tell 'em l'm handsome.
你也掰的太离谱了,奥斯卡
- Throw that in, say l'm buff. - You are going way too far.
其实...还不够离谱
Actually, he hasn't gone far enough.
没错!啥?
Exactly. What?
你得去宰鲨鱼,我得消失
You need to slay a shark, and l need to disappear.
咱们干脆这样...
Here's what we're gonna do.
这是凯蒂・辛文现场报导
Katie Current, reporting live.
- 我们得到还未经证实的报导... - 鲨鱼!
- We've had unconfirmed reports of a... - [fish screams] Shark!
[Lenny hums Theme From Jaws]
- 嗒-嗒-嗒 - 瞧,是屠鲨者
-  Da-da-da - Look. It's the Sharkslayer.
[chuckles]
[bellows]
嗒-嗒-嗒!
Da-da-da-da!
[snarls]
我的老天!拍到了吗?
Holy mackerel. Did we get that?
嗨,安姬,奥斯卡上电视了
Hey, Ang. Oscar's on the TV.
秀一下 给混蛋们点颜色看看
Show me that. Go ahead with your bad self.
你听到了吗,蓝尼?
Do you hear them, Lenny?
大家都疯狂了 他们爱死我们了
They are goin' crazy, man. They love us.
他们只爱你,却讨厌我 咱们换个角色吧
They love you. They hate me. Can we switch sides?
或许我可以演屠鱼者 他们绝对想不到
l can be the Fishslayer. They'll never see it coming.
少来,这是你的主意耶 这样你就不用回家了
Come on, man. You sell this, you'll never have to go home again.
你可以开始一个崭新的人生 来,吼一声给我听听
You can start a new life. Now gimme a growl.
好吧
Okay. [purrs]
[clears throat]
[roars]
- 像这样? - 好...好极了
- Like that? - That was... pretty good.
咱们走
Let's go.
你才付这点钱? 你可知道我的客户多厉害?
ls that all? Do you understand how huge my client is? Turn on your TV.
蓝尼,蓝尼!蓝尼!
Lenny. Lenny! Lenny!
[everyone gasps]
把电视关了,把电视关了
Turn off your TV. Turn off your TV.
别把我吞下去
[Oscar] Don't swallow.
- 奥斯卡? - 不是...我是小木偶皮诺丘!当然是我!
- Oscar? - No, it's Pinocchio. Of course it's me.
- 你干么呀你 - 对不起
- [Oscar] Why did you do that? - l'm sorry.
对不起,是你在电影院 踩到别人鳍的时候说的
No. ''Sorry'' is when you step on somebody's fin at the movies.
对不起,是你问人家什么时候生
''Sorry'' is when you say, ''When's the baby due?''
结果她的肚子只是一团肥油的时候说的
and it turns out the person's just fat.
对不起,还不能表达你歉意的万分之一
This is as far away from ''sorry'' as you could possibly get.
奥斯卡,我想吐
But, Oscar, l think l'm gonna puke.
别别别,蓝尼,慢慢把嘴张开
No, no. Lenny, just open up.
放松点
Nice and easy.
[Oscar strains]
[cheering]
你们看得高兴吗?
[Oscar] Are you not entertained?
实话说出来会吓死你们
You can't handle the truth.
我是你们的英雄
You had me at hello.
[  Elvis Vs JXL: A Little Less Conversation]
快把电视打开 关掉干嘛,快打开
Turn your TV back on. Why are you turning your TV off?
- [Oscar yells] - [cheering]
这礁镇的很,怎么找得到屠鲨者
This reef is huge. How we supposed to find the Sharkslayer?
[wailing]
- [thud] - [cheering]
到终场的高潮戏了,蓝尼 就像咱们排演的一样
This is it, Lenny. Big finish. Just like we practiced.
- 飞鱼? - 被打飞出去的鱼
- The flying fish? - The flying fish.
帮个忙吧,老兄
A little help here, buddy boy?
- 对不起 - 谢谢
- Sorry. - Thank you.
[screams]
[Lenny wails]
诅咒你...屠鲨者
Curse you, Sharkslayer.
[wails]
[quietens wails]
[makes crashing sound]
[sighs]
哼～你回去告诉唐・李诺
Yeah, and you tell Don Lame-o
我绝对绝对
that l don't never, ever, ever, never,
不要在这里再看到一只鲨鱼
want to see another shark on this reef again. Ever.
记住我的名号
Remember this name.
屠鲨者奥斯卡
Oscar the Sharkslayer.
哈,看到了吧,看到了吧
You see? You see?
奥斯卡! 奥斯卡!
[crowd chants] Oscar! Oscar!
- 耶 - 奥斯卡,万万岁
- Yay! - [crowd]  Oscar, boom bye-ay
奥斯卡,万万岁
Oscar, boom bye-ay
看看奥斯卡
Look at Oscar.
奥斯卡,万万岁 奥斯卡,万万岁
Oscar, boom bye-ay Oscar, boom bye-ay
喂...萝...
Woo! Hey... Lola.
似乎屠鲨者今天不只征服了几只鲨鱼
[TV] Seems The Sharkslayer not only conquered a few sharks today,
还征服了许多美人心
but maybe a few hearts?
难道最具价值的单身汉 已心有所属了吗?
Has the reef's most eligible bachelor been snapped up?
我是凯蒂・辛文,现场为您转播
I'm Katie Current, here live,
奥斯卡光荣的胜利
watching the Sharkslayer making out.
安姬,能递那个蓝色的给我吗?
Hey, Angie, can you hand me the blue one?
谢谢
Thank you.
啊呼,看看谁进来了? 哈哈
Look who stepped in the room! [laughs]
噢!
[laughs] Yeah!
奥斯卡和蓝尼合作无间,宝贝 来来来,击个掌...
Oscar and Lenny. What a team, baby. Give me that, give me some fin.
上拍...下拍...哈哈
High fin. Low fin.
你看到我了吗? 我像这样...
Yo, did you see me? l was like...
[makes kung fu noises]
我疯了
l was crazy.
当你捶我时,观众都大叫～啊...
When you punched me, and the crowd was...
对呀,他们都真以为我被吃了.
Yeah, they ate it up.
安姬,你也信以为真了,对吧
You didn't know l had it in me, did you?
- 简直是奥斯卡爆发秀 - 我演的如何?
- lt was like an Oscar-splosion. - How good was l?
- 最佳表演奖 - 谢谢...谢谢...
- You was the bomb. - Thank you. Thank you.
你这个...大众情人 晚间新闻我看到你了
And hey, hey, hey, Casanova. l saw your big finish on the news.
那个吻棒极了,调情圣手
Nice smooch, lover boy.
不该播的,这是隐私呀
lxnay on the isskay, man. That's private.
隐私? 全市的市民都看见了
Private? The entire reef saw you do it.
喔...嘿...有人心情不好 来,安姬,笑一个
Hey, somebody's in a bad mood. C'mon, Ang, lemme see that smile.
- 来笑一个,宝贝... - 少来
- Show me the smile, baby... - Knock it off.
- 你怎么啦? - 我?
- What has gotten into you? - Me?
我发誓,有时我真想把你的蠢脑袋...
l swear, sometimes l wanna take your big dumb dummy-head, and just...
安姬,安姬,到底是什么问题?
Ang, what is the problem?
问题?没问题,我什么问题也没有
Problem? No problem. l don't have a problem.
完美女郎才是问题
Miss Perfect is the one with the problem.
嗨～两位
Hey, you guys...
- 你对萝拉有什么不满吗? - 我的嘴可没说
- What do you got against Lola? - Not my lips, that's for sure.
- 怎么啦 - 我可不想被扯进去
- What's goin' on? - l'm gonna stay outta this one.
你管萝拉干嘛呀?
Why would you even care about Lola anyway?
- 我才不管咧 - 你不管?
- l don't. - You don't.
- 我不管 - 不管啥?
- No. - No what?
- 不知道 - 你们想...
- l don't know. - You wanna...
不!
[both] No!
奥斯卡,我很好奇,你干脆告诉我
Just tell me, Oscar, 'cause l'm curious.
为什么她会对你有兴趣?
Why do you think she's interested, huh?
如果你不是闻名遐迩的屠鲨者 她还会和你在一起?
Do you think for one minute that she'd even be with you
if you weren't the famous Sharkslayer?
- 你们...请别吵了 - 你怎么瞎了眼?
- Please, don't fight. - Are you blind?
起码她把我当成大人物
She treats me like l'm somebody.
- 如果你是无名小卒,她还会爱你吗? - 我默默无名的时候,没一个人爱我!
- Would she love you if you were nobody? - Nobody loved me as a nobody.
我爱你...
l did.
在你发财之前,也在你出名之前
Before the money, and before the fame.
在你骗人之前
Before the lie.
以前你还是个人物,奥斯卡
To me you were a somebody, Oscar.
现在你除了伪君子,什么都不是
Now you're nothing but a fake.
丢脸的骗子
A sham. A con.
一个小丑
You're a joke.
我来啦...
[Lenny] Here l come...
嗒-嗒! 史柏淳...会洗鲸的海豚
Ta-da! Sebastian the Whale-Washin' Dolphin.
- 安姬... - 算了!你走吧
- Angie... - No, forget it. Just go.
我不想再听你说 以前你拥有的一切都不值一文
l'm tired of hearing how everything you had in your life wasn't good enough.
包括我
lncluding me.
- 安姬? - 喔,嗨...对不起
- [Lenny] Angie? - Oh, Honey, l'm sorry.
你回去,然后再出来一次
Go, go back and do it again.
别这样
Hey, come on.
一切都会没事儿的
lt'll be OK.
[ lndia Arie: Get It Together]
# 当你看起来没事 心却碎了时 #
One shot to your heart without breaking your skin
# 除了亲人,没人能伤你这么深 #
No-one has the power to hurt you like your kin
# 一切都藏在心里 没告诉任何人 #
Kept it inside Didn't tell no-one else...
你自己却不敢 对自己承认
You can't handle the truth.
自己的臭嘴闻起来像鲨鱼
You've got Shark Breath.
# 只能怪你自己 #
And now you only have yourself to blame
# 如果你还继续这样 #
If you continue to live this way
# 振作起来 # # 你需要治愈身体创伤 #
-  Get it together -  You wanna heal your body
# 振作起来 # # 你需要治愈心灵创伤 #
-  Get it together -  You have to heal your heart
# 无论如何 #
Whatsoever...
你们小孩子在干嘛? 跟你们说过几次了?
What you kids doing? How many times l have to tell you?
已经过了睡觉时间,快去
lt's past your bed time. Go on.
喂,小鬼们在干嘛?
Hey. What are you kids up to?
看起来不错,你们可以靠这手艺吃饭啦
That looks pretty good. You should do this for a living.
# 你可以飞飞飞飞 #
You can fly, fly, fly, fly
# 你可以活 也可以死 #
You can live or you can die
# 一生之中有很多抉择 #
You know that life is a choice you make
# 你可以施予 也可以接纳 #
You can give or you can take
# 你可以飞飞飞飞 #
You can fly, fly, fly, fly
# 你可以飞飞… #
You can fly, fly...
欧式软膏
[deep voice] Preparation ''O''.
[欧式软膏可以宰了你的痔疮 和奥斯卡宰了鲨鱼一样轻松]
lt slays hemorrhoids like Oscar slays sharks.
嗨,奥斯卡
Hey, Oscar.
欧式软膏
[whale] Preparation O...
安姬说对了,我只是个小丑
Angie was right. l am a joke.
[tuts]
嗨,屠鲨者
Hey, Sharkslayer.
怎么一个人在外面? 你的朋友们都在里面
Why are you out here? All your friends are inside.
不是所有的朋友
Not all my friends.
你是指洗鲸场那个小妞?
You mean that little bottom feeder from the Whale Wash?
忘了她吧,她只是个小人物
Forget about her. She's a nobody.
No, l'm the nobody.
不,我才是小人物
[laughs]
呵呵...让我猜猜 她跟你说..."她爱你"
Oh, let me guess. She told you that she loves you.
对吧?
ls that it? [laughs]
这不表示你也爱她...呵呵
lt's not like you feel the same way about her. [laughs]
我不认为我们可以继续下去
You know, l don't think this is gonna work out.
等等,你是说你要甩了我?
Wait, are you dumping me?
让我解释些事情给你听
Let me explain something to you.
假装是你生日,咱们开派对
We're gonna party like it's your birthday
[thudding]
哈...年轻人火辣辣的爱
- Ha! Young love. - [partygoers laugh]
[ The Four Tops: I Can't Help Myself (Sugar Pie Honey Bunch)]
# 亲爱的甜心 #
Sugar-pie, honey-bunch
# 你知道我爱你 #
You know that I love you
# 我无法自制 #
I can't help myself
# 我只爱你一个 #
I love you and nobody else...
- 嗨,奥斯卡 - 现在不能说话,我得去找安姬
- Hey, Oscar! - l can't talk. l gotta find Angie.
我得告诉她...我爱她
l need to tell her l love her.
# 你来了又去 #
You come and you go...
这就对啦,奥斯卡
Way to go, Oscar.
- 喂,鲸鱼洗车... - 把电话给我
- lrie. Whale Wash, where you... - Gimme it.
- 你能享受极品洗车... - 把电话给我
- Where you get a whale of a wash... - Gimme the phone.
价钱...非常非常便宜 极品洗车,绝对超值
...and the price is very, very low, considering how good the wash is.
告诉你们多少次啦! 是"让你吓一跳"
How many times do l have to tell you? lt's ''gosh.''
让你享受极品洗车,价钱让你吓一跳
''You get a whale of a wash, and the price, oh, my gosh.''
- 懂了,懂了,老板
- Me gets it, man. - [telephone]
- 鲸鱼洗车? - 台词还押韵哩,呵呵
- Whale Wash? - Rhymes with gosh.
给我,你们两个滚一边去 别在这里闹场
Gimme that. Get outta here. Go be useless someplace else.
- 赛斯,安姬在哪儿?
- Sykes, where's Angie? - [telephone]
鲸鱼洗车,极品洗车
Whale Wash, you get a whale of a wash...
找你的
lt's for you.
哈?
Hello?
- 是屠鲨者吗? - 是. 你是谁呀?
- Is this the Sharkslayer? - Yeah, who's this?
是路卡...你别管我是谁
lt's Luca the Octo... l mean, forget about it.
你把游戏规则给我听好了
Now you follow these instructions to the letter, OK?
档案柜最上面的抽屉 有个包包...拿出来
File cabinet. Top drawer. There's a package. Get it.
看到了吧...狠角色 你的女人在咱们手上
That's right, tough guy, we've got your girl.
咱们得坐下谈谈,一个钟头后
There's a sit-down in one hour.
- 谁呀? - 嘘!
- Who is it? - Shh!
如果不来,我就让她和其他的鱼一起睡
Be there, if you don't wanna see her sleepin' with the fishes.
和死鱼睡
The dead ones.
如果你听懂了,就点头
Now, nod your head if you understand.
你点头了吗?
Now, tell me if you nodded your head.
我点了
l nodded.
[dialling tone]
安姬被抓走了,他们要谈判
They got Angie. And they want a sit-down.
我不让任何人受到伤害,尤其是安姬
l never meant for anybody to get hurt, especially not Angie.
都是我的错
This is all my fault.
这是典型的黑帮手段,我见多了
Classic move. l've seen it a thousand times.
他们利用你的最爱来反制你
They take the thing you love the most, and then they use it against you.
我们得去谈判,得去救她
We gotta go to that sit-down and we gotta save her.
喔喔喔,看,我也想救她
Whoa. Look, l wanna save Angie, too,
但我可不能跳着华尔兹进去说 "嗨,老爸,我是只海豚"
but l can't waltz in and say, ''Hi, Pop. l'm a dolphin.''
- 蓝尼? - 还有屠鲨者是假的
- Lenny? - And the Sharkslayer's a fake.
假的?
Fake?
我们得有更好的计画
We're gonna need a better plan than that.
是开玩笑的吧?
[laughs] This is a joke, right?
因为我跟李诺说...
Because l told Lino...
闭嘴,李诺...闭嘴
[Sykes] Shut up, Lino. Shut up.
告诉我,他也不是蓝尼
[high-pitched] Tell me that's not Lenny.
- 你是真的屠鲨者 - 对不起,赛斯,我不是
- Tell me you're a real Sharkslayer. - l'm sorry, Sykes, l'm not.
但是其他鲨鱼并不知道
But the sharks don't know that.
[both gulp]
[hyperventilates]
[shark coughs]
[both gasp in terror]
- [snarls] - [all shriek]
别乱搞好不? 这行不通的,我们死定了
Will you stop screwin' around? This'll never work. We're dead.
谢谢...赛斯,谢谢...
Thank you, Sykes. Thank you.
我手下赛斯,刚才恳求我
My man Sykes just begged me
不要宰了在场你们所有人
not to murder-lise all y'all up in here.
我或许会听他的,也可能不会
Now, l might listen to him, but then again l might not.
那得看看你们每一个人表现如何
And that depends on the individual behavior
在场每个人的,个人表现
of all the individuals in here, individually.
对吧?
Ain't that right?
瞧,他手下有只海豚
Look, he's got dolphin muscle.
我叔叔维托就吃过海豚的亏
My uncle Vito got whacked by one of those.
好了,是哪只沙丁鱼说要谈判的?
Now which one of you sardines called this meeting?
那...就是我
- That would be me. - [door slams]
我说...你就是屠鲨者
So, this is the Sharkslayer.
我一直都很想见你
l've been lookin' forward to meeting you.
感觉咱们好像一家人,你觉得呢?
l feel like we're practically family. You know that?
很奇怪,不是吗?
Funny, ain't it?
我把我的孩子们带到这世上 给他们爱与关怀
l brought my kids into the world, full of love and care,
你却把他们夺走
and you took them out.
知道我是谁吗? 你...知道我是谁吗?
You know who l am? Do you know who l am?
我是唐,大白鲨黑帮的教父
l'm the Don. The boss of the Great White Sharks.
老板,我留了个位子给你
Hey, boss, l saved you a seat.
在你出生前,这儿就是我的地盘
l've been runnin' this reef since before you was born.
如果你以为我治不了你...
And if you thought a guy like me can't get to a guy like you...
告诉你吧,你错了
Guess what? You thought wrong.
[muffled screams]
老兄,是你错了吧
Pah. Man, you the one who's wrong.
我几乎不认识她,小姐,你叫什么名字?
l barely even know that girl. What's your name, miss?
真的? 我说,他是打肿脸充胖子
Oh, yeah? Well, l say he's bluffing.
- 莫若,如果我还没结婚的话... - 你好吗,靓妞?
- Marone, if l wasn't married... - How ya doin', pretty lady?
萝拉,咱们又见面了
Lola. We meet again.
屠鲨者,你知道吗...我最爱的还不算是钱
You know, Sharkslayer, there's only one thing l like better than money.
是复仇
Revenge.
哦...我恋爱了
- [sharks swoon] - Oh! l'm in love.
你是屠鲨者的日子已经过去了
Your sharkslayin' days are over.
你无计可施了
And there ain't nothing you can do about it.
[Oscar laughs]
[Lenny and Sykes laugh]
- 有啥好笑的? - 噢
- Huh? What's so funny? - Ow.
你啥也没有,啥也没有
You got nothing. Nothing.
施柏淳,把她解决了
Sebastian, take her out.
[Oscar hums U Can't Touch This]
碰不到,啦啦啦
Can't touch this.
哦哦,哦哦,哦哦,哦哦
Oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh
停下,奥斯卡秀的时间
Stop. Oscar time.
好了,新规矩
OK, new rules.
没人...再说一次,没人... 未经我允许,可以乱动
Nobody, l repeat, nobody, makes a move without my OK.
我现在是巴拿马运河,宝贝们
l am the Panama Canal, baby.
现在开始,每个人都得经过我这关
From now on, everything flows through me.
啥? 他干嘛了? 我看不见!
What'd he do? l can't see it.
如果你掉了颗牙 没有我允许,不准长颗新的,懂吗?
You don't lose a tooth, you don't grow one back without my OK, OK?
懂
OK.
如果你打喷嚏 没有我允许,不准擦鼻涕,懂吗?
lf you sneeze, you don't wipe that boogie without my OK, OK?
懂
OK.
没有我允许,你也不准说懂
And you don't say ''OK'' without my OK.
- 懂吗?
- OK? - [shark whimpers]
噢噢,好啦,谢谢你们的到来,得走了
Oh-oh. OK, thank you all for coming. We gotta go.
哦,对了,还有一件事 你们搞什么鬼,怎么会住在爱之船上?
One more thing. What's with all y'all living in the Love Boat?
- 奥斯卡 - 你们是黑帮耶
- Oscar. - Y'all are supposed to be the mob.
- 该找个真正的隐匿处 - 奥斯卡
- Get yourselves a real hideout. - [gags] Oscar.
看好了,李诺
And take a good look, Lino.
你玩完了,你过气了
lt's over. You're old school.
- 奥斯卡 - 干嘛?
- Oscar. - What?
[retches]
The horror. The horror.
[Lenny] The horror. The horror.
呃...对不起
[laughs sheepishly] Um... excuse me.
- 安姬,你没事吧 - 怎么会没事
- Ang, are you OK? - No, l'm not OK.
他吃了我...
He ate me..
我实在受不了,味道太恶心了
l couldn't take it. The taste was killin' me.
蓝尼?
Lenny?
是你吗?
ls that you?
你还活着?
You're alive?
我以为失去你了
l thought l lost you.
你穿的是啥?啥玩意儿?
What are you wearing? Huh? What is that?
[gasps of astonishment]
老板,是蓝尼 他易容了,所以我们认不出他来
Boss, it's Lenny. He was wearing a disguise so we wouldn't recognize him,
现在他恢复原貌,所以我们就认出来啦
but now he's not wearing a disguise, so we do recognize him.
- 嗨,老爸 - 你搞啥?
- Hi, Pop. - Are you kiddin' me?
你搞啥? 你疯啦!
Are you kiddin' me? Are you outta your mind?
你知道自己看起来像啥吗?
Do you have any idea how this looks?
这是我参加过最精彩的谈判
This is the best sit-down l've ever been to.
你怎么会跟他在一起 他杀的你的亲兄弟法兰奇呀
What are you doing with him? He took out your flesh and blood, Frankie.
- 可是,老爸,听我解释... - 没有可是
- But, Pop, listen... - But nothing.
你决不能背叛自己的亲人,绝不
You never take sides against the family. Ever.
喂...唐...李诺...先生 听着,这不是他的错,是咱们之间的恩怨
Hey, Don. Lino. Sir. lt's not his fault. This is between you and me.
我又没把你怎样
What did l ever do to you?
你怎能杀了法兰奇,又把蓝尼变成了海豚
You took Frankie away and you turned Lenny into a dolphin.
我决不会放过你
l'm gonna get you.
- 奥斯卡,小心 - 奥斯卡,快逃,快逃命
- [Angie] Oscar, look out. - Oscar, swim. Swim for your life.
从你成为屠鲨者那天起 你就一定会后悔
You're gonna regret the day you became the Sharkslayer.
噢,噢,噢
Well, well, well.
看看谁被舷窗口卡住了
Look who's stuck in the porthole.
大块头,你还饿吗?
You still hungry, big guy?
跟我的小朋友们打声招呼吧
Well, say hello to my little friends.
- [buzzing] - [hums cavalry charge]
[wails]
- 再试一次 - 鲸鱼洗车
- Try it again. - Whale Wash,
极品洗车,价钱是...
you get a whale of a wash and the price...
哇～吓我一跳!
Oh, my gosh.
成了,你终于说对啦
All right. You got it right.
大家让开
Everybody out of the way.
- 快逃 - 鲨鱼!
- Blow out. - Shark!
来吧,李诺 该是给你洗洗干净的时候了
Come on, Lino, it's time to clean up your act.
爸,放了他吧!
Pop, leave him alone.
好了,李诺...游戏结束
All right, Lino. Game's over.
- 蓝尼?你怎么会在这儿? - 对不起
- Lenny? What are you doing in there? - Sorry.
李诺在哪儿?
Where's Lino?
- 他就在我后面,对吧? - 你是我的了
- He's right behind me, isn't he? - You're mine now.
哇!
Whoa!
屠鲨者,是解决问题的时候了
Let's finish this, Sharkslayer.
哦,正是时候
Oh, we're about to.
[whirring]
感谢光临鲸鱼洗车
- [music on headphones] - Thank you for coming to Whale Wash.
[muttering]
好啦,有谁能帮我弄出这泡泡
OK, somebody needs to get me out of the bubble.
今天
- Today. - [pop]
- 安姬... - 屠鲨者,再次胜利
- Angie... - The Sharkslayer does it again.
这次把两只鲨鱼,引进了致命的陷阱
This time, luring two sharks into his death-trap of hygiene.
奥斯卡,每个人都梦想成为你
Oscar, you're the somebody everybody wants to be.
在食物链的最上面,谈谈你成为偶像的感受
The top of the food chain. Tell our cameras how it feels to be you.
- 安姬 - 奥斯卡,快帮我弄出去
- Angie. - Oscar, get me outta here, quick.
我要先跑了,越远越好
l need a head start to get as far away as possible.
- 你把他怎么啦 - 不...都是误会
- Look what you did to him. - lt's a misunderstanding.
屠鲨者,过来这里
Sharkslayer. Over here.
屠鲨者...屠鲨者...
[chant] Sharkslayer. Sharkslayer.
停!
Stop!
我不是真的屠鲨者!
l am not a real Sharkslayer!
[everyone gasps]
- 我撒了谎 - 啥?
- l lied. - What?
我也不是真的财务顾问
And l'm not a real financial advisor. [sobs]
法兰奇是被锚砸死的
OK. lt was an anchor that killed Frankie.
我跟他的死没关系,蓝尼也没有
l didn't have anything to do with it, and neither did Lenny.
如果是真的,那你干嘛要逃走?
lf that was true, why did you run away?
因为你总是想让我和法兰奇一样
Because you always wanted me to be like Frankie.
我永远成不了你心目中真正的鲨鱼
l'll never be the shark you want me to be.
你到底是哪里不对?
What is your problem?
你儿子喜欢助人,他最好的朋友是鱼
So your son likes kelp. So his best friend is a fish.
他喜欢打扮成海豚,这又如何?
So he likes to dress like a dolphin. So what?
大家就喜欢他这个样子
Everybody loves him just the way he is.
你为什么不能?
Why can't you?
别犯和我一样的错误
Don't make the same mistake that l did.
以前我不懂我拥有什么 直到失去才明白
l didn't know what l had until l lost it.
放我下来
Will you get me outta this
我才能抱抱我儿子,告诉他我错了
so l can hug my kid and tell him l'm sorry?
老爸
Pop.
[whirring]
你过来
Come here, you.
儿子,不管你吃什么,穿什么,我都爱你
l love you, Son, no matter what you eat, or how you dress.
奥斯卡?
[Angie] Oscar?
安姬?
Angie?
安姬,我希望我以前像现在这样明白
Angie, l wish l knew now what l knew then.
我是说,我希望你明白我所明白的
l mean, l wish you knew what l knew,
我是说...在这之前
l mean, before this...
- 都被你说砸了,老兄 - 别管闲事
- You're blowin' it, man. - Mind your business.
现在是很感性,很紧张的一刻
lt's emotional and it's pressure.
我是说...我只是...
What l'm saying, l just...
我根本不在乎住礁顶
l didn't need the top of the reef.
一切我想要的...就在我面前,一直都在
Everything l wanted was right there in front of me the whole time.
那出人头地的事怎么办?
Well, what about being a somebody?
没有你,我谁也不是
l'm nobody without you.
[bells jingle]
[Joe makes smoochy noises]
你扯我后腿呀
You're not helping.
过来...你这...大傻瓜
Come here, you big dumb dummy-head.
我以前从没告诉过你们 你俩儿是我最忠实的部属
l never told you two this, but you're the best henchman a guy ever had.
来吧,一起拥抱一下
C'mon, group hug.
抱歉,老板
Sorry, man.
来吧,塞斯,再试一次,别担心
Come, Sykes, try again, mon. Don't fret.
不必了,没那心情了
Forget it. The moment's gone.
我说...李诺...唐
So, uh, Lino... Uh, Don...
我们没事了吧? 我的意思是礁镇市民没事了吧?
We cool, right? l mean, like the reef is safe?
我们以后走在街上不必像这样吧? 啊啊,你明白我的意思
Walk the streets, you know, without... aaah! You know.
是啊,没事了
Yeah, we're cool.
[cheering]
奥斯卡,打扰
Oscar. Excuse me.
你失去了拚命撒谎所得来的一切
You've lost everything you lied so hard to achieve.
告诉我,那你下一步想要什么呢?
Tell me, what's next for you?
快呀,大家都在等,总经理先生
Come on, everyone's waiting, Mr. Manager.
好了,把我的新办公桌做最后的装饰
All right, l just gotta put the finishing touch on my new desk.
我爱你,老爸
Love ya, Pop.
- 喂 - 赛斯
- Yo, dog. - Sykes.
好了,伙伴,现在看你表演了
All right, partner, let's see what you can do.
赛斯+奥斯卡鲸鱼洗车场正式开张营业
Sykes and Oscar's Whale Wash is now open for business.
[ Car Wash]
大家...一起...来派对
Yo, E, B. Let's get this party bumpin'.
哟哟,是而尼和伯尼在操刀
Yo, yo. lt's E and B on the wheels of steel.
克丽丝汀,蜜丝
Yo, Christina. Missy.
给大家来点儿奥斯卡式乐子,怎么样?
How about we have a little Oscar-licious fun?
# 小鲔鱼想成大事 #
Yo, small tuna fish, I'm one big catch
# 你或许永远发不了财 #
You might not ever get rich
# 埋头苦干 #
Let me tell you, it's better than diggin' a ditch
# 总会有机会 #
There ain't no tellin' who you might meet...
别在家试这个
[Oscar] Don't try this at home.
# 电影明星或只是个普通小偷 #
A movie star or maybe a common thief
# 在洗车店工作 # # 噢噢耶耶 #
-  Workin' at the car wash -  Whoa whoa yeah yeah
# 在洗车店 # # 噢耶 #
-  At the car wash, yeah -  Ooh, yeah
# 在洗车店 # # 和我一起唱 #
-  At the car wash -  Sing it with me...
嗨,安姬 对不起,我和爸来晚了
Hey, Angie, sorry Pop and l are late,
但是我们带了些新客人来
but we brought some new customers.
嗨,你好吗?
Hey, how ya doin'?
哇噢
Wow.
大伙儿,快进去吧
OK, guys, come on in.
# 成明星不是不可能 #
This ain't no place to be if you're planning on being a star
# 告诉你什么都可能 #
Let me tell you it's always cool
# 老板不在乎你有时候像个傻瓜 #
And the boss don't mind sometimes if you're acting like a fool
-  # 在洗车店工作 # - 不不...是击掌,你没击
-  Working at the car wash... - No, snap it. You're not snapping it.
我在击,我在击
l'm snapping it.
- 没关系,很多白鲨都不会 - 呦?
- A lot of great whites can't do it, yo. - Yo?
- 呦...啥? - 什么啥?
- Yo, what's up? - Up with what?
呦呦呦...呦呦呦...
Yo, yo, yo. Yo, yo, yo. Yo, yo...
你再呦一次
You say ''yo'' one more time,
- 我就把你呦了 - 对不起
- l'm gonna yo you. - Sorry.
- 好啦,搞定你的外装了 - 好
- OK, doo, l pimped your hide. - All right.
喂～很好笑吗?
Hey. You think this is funny?
我看起来像个小丑不成?
What am l, a clown to you?
# 洗车 #
Car wash
# 水里的鲨鱼不再吃人 #
Sharks in the water Make theirjaws lock
# 当我振作起来,我成了热门人物 #
When I swim through the grim I'm too hot
# 你们可以赌赌看 # # 你们都是小鲔鱼 #
You can make y'all bets Y'all small tuna fish
# 我是大人物 # # 屠鲨者 #
-  I'm one big catch -  Sharkslayer
# 遵从规则 #
Bow down player...
- 你有啥? - 你肯定会要
- What you got? - You don't want none of this.
你搞什么呀 伙计们,散开
You gotta be kidding. Break it down, fellas.
9 to 5 I gotta keep that fat stack comin'...
You got served.
Workin' at the car wash
Hey yeah
At the car wash, yeah
Come on, work, baby, work it Sing it
-  At the car wash -  Hey yeah
At the car wash, yeah
Come on, work, baby, work it Sing it
At the car wash
Workin' at the car wash, yeah
So come on, come on, come on, come on
Now keep it comin'
# 你也许不会富有,但是嘿 #
You may not ever get rich, but hey
鲨鱼故事独一无二
A Shark Tale exclusive
Ooh, hey
Get your car washed today
[ D12: Lies And Rumors]
[bell]
有人吗?有人吗?
Hello? Hello.
奥斯卡?听着,宝贝,我知道我是个坏女孩
Oscar? Listen, baby, l know l was a bad girl,
但是,得了 不让我回来你就是疯了
but, come on, you'd have to be crazy not to take me back.
有人提到疯了?
Did someone say crazy?
[ Justin Timberlake & Timbaland: Good Foot]
出租车
Taxi.
嘿,出租车
Hey, taxi.
喂!
Hello.
嗨,你还要吃完剩下的爆米花?
Hi. You gonna eat the rest of your popcorn?
呕~白脱太多了
Eurgh! Too much butter.
嘿,玉米片
Hey, a nacho.
[siren]
[ Mary J Blige: Got To Be Real]
一半还没到呢,哈哈哈
You're not even halfway done yet.
[ Cheryl Lynn: Sweet Kind Of Life]
什么?看见这家伙没? 他几乎没在电影里做什么
What? You see this guy? He hardly worked on the movie at all.
总是在电话里"叽里咕噜叽里咕噜"
Always on the phone. Yakkin', yakkin', yakkin'.
[ Pussy Cat Dolls: We Went As Far As We Felt Like Going]
老兄,有没看见隔壁在放什么?
Man, have you guys seen what's playing next door?
真恶~
Stinky.
你还在做什么?出去出去,都过了你睡觉时间了
What you doing? Go on, get outta here. lt's past your bedtime.